That is the stupidest thing you can ever
那是你所能做的最愚蠢的事
do.
。   对于
someone who's just trying to grow their
只想让财富增值的人来说，最重要的是什么
money?
？
So, I learned this from my mother and I
我是从我母亲那里学到这个的，然后我围绕
it. Yeah, there she is. So,
它建立了一家公司。 对，她在那儿。
I haven't seen that picture in a while.
我已经很久没看到那张照片了。
Damn. I mean, what she did, the
该死。 我的意思是，她所做的一切，她的
performance was extraordinary. And with
表演非常出色。 就
that, she put my brother and I through
这样，她供我和哥哥上了
college. She took care of her family
大学。
when they fell on hard times. When I saw
当家人陷入困境时，她照顾了他们。 当我看到
the results, I said, "That's it. That's
结果时，我说：“就这么定了。
how I'm going to invest for the rest of
我这辈子都要这样投资
my life."
。”
So, talk me through this. I want as much
请你详细地给我解释一下。 我希望了解
detail as possible.
尽可能多的细节。
Okay, let's start with this.
好的，我们就从这里开始。
Kevin Oly aka Mr. Wonderful, is the
凯文·奥利，又名“神奇先生”，是一位
self-made millionaire and investor
白手起家的百万富翁和投资人，他
who's built and sold companies for
创建并出售了价值数
billions. There's a lot of people don't
十亿美元的公司。 很多人因为
like me for my blindness. I don't care
我失明而不喜欢我。 我不在乎，
because there's people that don't think
因为有些人不考虑
ahead and find themselves mired in debt
长远，结果深陷债务泥潭，
but then pissing away money spending $28
然后又挥霍金钱，花 28 美元吃顿
for lunch. I mean that's just stupid.
午饭。 我的意思是，这简直太愚蠢了。   那
What about a house?
房子呢？
The mistake that people make is they buy
人们犯的错误是买的
too much house. Never let the mortgage
房子太大了。 房贷
and the cost of maintaining the house be
和房屋维护费用绝不能
more than 1/3 of your income.
超过你收入的三分之一。
Now how much does the person that you
那么，你爱上的那个人究竟会对你产生多大的
fall in love with have an impact?
影响呢？
You kidding? It's everything. And I did
你在开玩笑吗？ 它包含了一切。 我做了
some research and most marriages can
一些调查，发现大多数婚姻都能
survive infidelity. They can't survive
经受住婚外情的考验。 他们无法承受
financial stress. But if everybody
经济压力。 但如果所有
that's listening does this one thing,
听众都做这件事，
you will have over a million and a half
你就能得到超过一百五十万
dollars.
美元。
Kevin, can anybody be an entrepreneur?
凯文，任何人都可以成为企业家吗？
No. Only a third of people can become
不，只有三分之一的人能成为
successful entrepreneurs because there's
成功的企业家，因为
to be successful. First,
要成功，你必须做到几件事。 首先，
[Music]
[音乐]
Kevin, I'm going to ask you to do
凯文，我要请你做一件
something which is quite difficult
相当困难的事情，
because I'd find it quite hard if
因为如果
someone asked me to do this. But before
有人请我这样做，我会觉得很难。 但在
we get into the detail, can you give me
我们深入探讨细节之前，您能否从
a 30,000 foot view on your
宏观角度概述一下您的
entrepreneurship and investing career?
创业和投资生涯？   在深入探讨
into those specifics.
具体细节之前，我们先来看三个最相关的要点。
Every entrepreneur I've ever talked to
我接触过的每一位企业家，如果能达到
um that finds himself where I am today
我今天的成就，他们都有
has has a defining moment where they are
一个决定性的时刻，将他们
pushed into this path. It's it's
推向了这条道路。 这是
something they can remember and they
他们可以记住的，而且会
remember it in perpetuity. And I'll
永远记住。 我永远不会
remember my moment getting fired in an
忘记我在冰淇淋店被解雇的那一刻
ice cream store. That simple. First day
。 就这么简单。 上班第一天
on the job, asked to serve and scoop ice
，就被安排去卖冰淇淋和舀
cream. And um I did that all day. But
冰淇淋。 嗯，我一整天都在做这件事。 但是
when people sample ice cream, they get a
当人们品尝冰淇淋时，他们会
taster and they take their gum out and
拿出口香糖，然后
they throw it on the floor. Somebody's
扔到地上。 一天结束的时候，总得有人把
got to scrape the gum off the floor at
地板上的口香糖刮掉
the end of the day. I only took that job
。 我之所以接受那份工作，是
because I was very interested in a girl
因为我非常喜欢鞋店里的一个女孩，
who's working in the shoe store and I
我
figured
想着下班
afterwards. And uh I saw her waiting for
后可以和她出去玩。 然后，我看到她在等
me and the woman who owned the store
我，店主
said, "You've got a scrape to come off
说：“你得从
the floor." And I didn't want her to see
地上起来了。” 我不想让她看到
me on my knees with a scraper. Bad for
我跪在地上拿着刮刀的样子。 对
my brand. I was in high school. And uh
我的品牌形象不利。 我当时还在上高中。 然后
she said, "No, no, you have to do it."
她说：“不，不，你必须这么做。”
And I said, "You know, you hired me as a
我说：“你知道，你雇我来是做
scooper, not a scraper." She said, "Um,
铲雪工，而不是做刮雪工。” 她说：“嗯，那
how about you're fired?" And I didn't
你被解雇怎么样？” 我当时并不
know what that meant. And it was the
知道那是什么意思。
defining moment for me because I
对我来说，这是一个决定性的时刻，因为我
realized there's two kinds of people in
意识到世界上有两种人
the world. There's people that own the
。 有些人是店主，
store and there's people that scrape the
有些人是负责清理
[__] off the floor and you have to
地板上污渍的人，你必须
decide who you are. And I'm not saying
决定自己属于哪一类人。 我并不是说当
being an employee is a bad thing. Not at
雇员不好。 一点也不
all. But for me, um, it it hit me. It
。 但对我来说，嗯，它深深地触动了我。 我突然
just hit me.
意识到了。
Kevin, there's a present for you. We
凯文，这是给你的礼物。 我们给
give a present to all of our guests.
所有来宾都准备了礼物。
Really?
真的吗？   在
Underneath that black
黑色下面，
Can I open it?
我可以打开它吗？
You can open it.
你可以打开它。
I just take this off.
我把它脱下来。
Oh, look at that.
哦，你看。
You've heard the story.
你听过这个故事了。
That is exactly how it looked except it
看起来就是这样，只不过
was black gum and that was exactly the
是黑色的口香糖，而且
tile. It was just like that Mexican
瓷砖也是黑色的。 它就像那种墨西哥
tile. That's really freaking me out.
瓷砖一样。 这真的让我很害怕。
So you were asked to scrape gum off a
所以，你被要求像这样把墨西哥瓷砖上的口香糖刮掉
just like that. And in order to do that,
。 为了做到这一点，
you got to get down on your knees and do
你必须跪下来去做
it. And um I just couldn't do it. And I
。 嗯……我就是做不到。 然后我，
and I and then you know the rest of the
然后我，然后你们就知道剩下的
story. I eventually could afford to
故事了。 如果我愿意，我最终有能力把
bulldoze the whole mall if I went to.
整个购物中心夷为平地。
when we went back to meet her and thank
当我们回去见她，感谢
her for her pushing you off the
她把你从
treadmill into that direction and she
跑步机上推向那个方向时，她已经
was gone and there was a bodega there
走了，取而代之的是一家杂货店
instead.
。
You said there that you realize that
你在那里说过，你意识到
there's kind of two people in life.
生活中其实有两种人。
There's the entrepreneurs, the person
有创业者，也就是
that owns the ice cream parlor and
冰淇淋店的老板；
there's the person that scrapes it off
还有负责把冰淇淋从地上刮下来的人
the floor.
。   是的
Yeah.
。
That provoked a question in me which is
这让我产生了一个疑问：
do you think anybody can own the ice
你认为任何人都可以拥有
cream parlor? I do you think anybody can
冰淇淋店吗？ 你认为任何人都可以
be an entrepreneur?
成为企业家吗？
No. I've tried to teach it. Um and I
不，我试过教。 嗯，我
mentor out it all the time to the CEOs
经常向与
that I work with. Uh there are some
我共事的CEO们提供指导。 嗯，有些
attributes of people that can do this. A
人具备一些特质，使他们能够做到这一点。
certain element of risk tolerance, uh a
一定的风险承受能力，以及
certain element of focus.
一定的专注力。
And then the other element which I've
最近我
really started to believe in of late is
开始真正相信的另一个因素是因果报应和
karma, luck. You need to be lucky. You
运气。 你需要一点运气。 你
need It's like Napoleon was once asked,
需要明白，这就像有人曾经问拿破仑：
"Who are your favorite generals?" and he
“你最喜欢的将军是谁？” 他
said, "My favorite generals are lucky
说：“我最喜欢的将军都是幸运的
generals. My lucky generals." And I'm
将军。我的幸运将军们。” 我
starting to think that in life, um,
开始觉得，在生活中，尤其是在
particular entrepreneurship, you look at
创业领域，你会注意到成功
the difference, the path of success and
与失败之间的区别，以及成功与
failure, and I nobody's exposed to it
失败的道路，而就我几十年来可能进行的投资数量而言，没有人比我更了解这一点
decades.
。
I think if you want a percentage, you
我想如果你想要一个百分比，你
know, I teach these cohorts at Harvard.
知道，我在哈佛大学教这些班级的学生。
I'm an executive fellow there. I'm very
我是那里的高级研究员。 我
proud of that work.
为这项工作感到非常自豪。
You get a class of 120 people in a room,
假设一个教室里有 120 人，
twothirds of them want to become
其中三分之二的人想成为
consultants. That's why they're there.
咨询顾问。 这就是他们在那里的原因。   他们
And lead a life of mediocrity and never
过着平庸的生活，一生中从未
make a decision of consequence in their
做出过任何有意义的决定
lives. And after 24 months, they are
。  24个月后，他们将
tainted with that disease forever.
永远带有这种疾病的烙印。
They'll always be good consultants, but
他们永远都会是优秀的顾问，但
they will never achieve greatness in any
他们永远不可能在任何方面取得伟大成就
way. In life, only a third of people can
。 人生中，只有三分之一的人能够
become successful entrepreneurs. That's
成为成功的企业家。 就是这样。 其余的人也
it. And the rest can be very successful
都能成为非常成功的
employees. And there's nothing wrong
员工。 这没什么错
with that. You can have a fantastic
。 你可以拥有精彩的
life. You won't be shackled to the, you
人生。 你不会被
entrepreneurship, the challenge of it,
创业的起起落落、挑战和
how hard it is, but you'll never be
艰辛所束缚，但你永远不会获得真正的
free. And that's the debate. That's it
自由。 这就是争论的焦点。 就是这样
right there. Do you want personal
。 你想要个人
freedom? It's the only path. That's it.
自由吗？ 这是唯一的出路。 就是这样。
It's the only path.
这是唯一的出路。
It is the only path. I mean, you can't I
这是唯一的出路。 我的意思是，你不能……
I've always said it's not about the
我一直都说，这不是为了
pursuit of money. It's not about the
追求金钱。 这不是为了
pursuit of greed. You will fail if you
满足贪婪。 你那样做会失败的
do that. It's it's the undying love of
。 这是对自由永不磨灭的热爱
freedom.
。
So that one-third of people that you say
所以，你所说的三分之一的人
will be successful, they'll pursue their
将会成功，他们会追求自己的
their dreams, they'll build a business,
梦想，他们会建立自己的事业，
whatever it might be.
无论是什么事业。   是的
Yeah.
。
Do you think it's possible for us in
你认为我们通过
this conversation to increase the
这次对话有可能提高
probability of their success? You said
他们成功的概率吗？ 你说
you don't think you can you can make
你认为你不能把
someone an entrepreneur,
某人培养成企业家，
but is there things you can do to
但是有没有什么方法可以
increase their probability of success?
提高他们成功的概率呢？
Yes, there are a couple of things that
是的，要想
you must achieve to be successful. And
成功，你必须做到几件事。
let me explain what they would be. And
让我来解释一下它们是什么。
this is not some academic study. This is
这并非什么学术研究。 这是来自
CEOs I've worked with and learned from
我曾共事和学习过的真实CEO的真实情况的真实数据，
because I used to work for guys like
因为我
Steve Jobs and others in my career.
职业生涯中曾为像史蒂夫·乔布斯这样的人工作过。
Let me um let me give you one that I
让我……让我给你举个例子，我
think is very important. We'll start
认为这一点非常重要。 我们就
with this one. I used to work for Steve
从这个开始吧。 上世纪90年代初，我曾在史蒂夫·乔布斯手下工作，负责
Jobs in the early 90s making all of his
开发他所有的
educational software. I mean it was just
教育软件。 我的意思是，当时的感觉就是：
Oh, there they are. My goodness, you
哦，他们在那儿。 我的天，你们的
guys do good research. Those are the
研究做得真好。
kind of things that we did for him, you
你知道，我们就是为他做这些事的
know.
。   是的
Yeah. Yeah. All of that. It's hard to
。 是的。 所有这些。 很难
find. Those are senior realms. But, you
找到。 这些都是高级领域。 但是，你
know, in developing that software,
知道，在开发该软件时，
we used to go quarterly. Um Heidi Rosen
我们过去是按季度进行的。 海蒂·罗森当时也在
was there in the room. She's still a a
房间里。 她仍然是一位
very famous venture capitalist.
非常著名的风险投资家。
And I would say, Steve, you know,
我想说，史蒂夫，你知道，
we got to do some market research on
我们得对《俄勒冈之旅》做一些市场调查
Oregon Trail. I mean, it's a huge title.
。 我的意思是，这可是个响当当的头衔。
It's in 110,000 school buildings. We got
它存在于 11 万栋学校建筑中。 我们
to do an update. It's going to cost you
需要进行一次更新。 这要花你
12 15 million bucks. We want to find out
1200万到1500万美元。 我们想了解
what the students want. We want to find
学生们想要什么。 我们想
out what the teachers want. Want to find
了解老师们的想法。 想
out what the parents want. Steve would
知道家长们想要什么。 顺便说一句，史蒂夫会
say, by the way, not a nice guy. Not a
说，他可不是什么好人。 他不是个
nice guy. He would say to a room full of
好人。 他会对满屋子的
people, Kevin, I don't give a [__] what
人说：“凯文，我根本不在乎
the students want or the parents think
学生想要什么，家长怎么想，
or anybody thinks. It's what I want.
或者任何人怎么想。” 这就是我想要的。
They don't know what they want till I
他们不知道自己想要什么，直到我
tell them what they want.
告诉他们他们想要什么。
And I said, "Steve, you sound like such
我说：“史蒂夫，你说话的语气简直像个
an [__] You have no idea what that
混蛋。你根本不知道那样
sounds like." He says, "No, no, that's
说话是什么感觉。” 他说：“不，不，就是这样
how it is, Kevin. Now, are you making
，凯文。现在，你
money with me? Are we Are you Am I your
跟我合作赚钱了吗？我们……你……我是你
fastest growing OEM? Have we not been
增长最快的OEM客户吗？我们不是已经
wildly successful and continue to be?" I
非常成功，而且还在继续成功吗？” 我
said, "Yes, Steve, that's true." He
说：“是的，史蒂夫，没错。” 他
said, "Then [__] shut up and do what
说：“那就他妈的闭嘴，照
I say."
我说的做。”
That's how he would talk to you.
他会那样跟你说话。
100%.
100%。
And here's what I learned.
以下是我学到的东西。
Look how wildly successful he was. But
看看他取得了多么巨大的成功。
here's why.
原因如下。
then in the early 90s of signal to noise
在 90 年代初期，很少有人关注
ratio.
信噪比这个概念，但他却理解了它。
that I tell every CEO now and I don't
我现在跟每个CEO都讲乔布斯身上最杰出的品质，
care if you're an S&amp;P 500 CEO or you're
无论你是标普500指数公司的CEO，还是
just starting a business.
刚刚创业的CEO，我都一样。
His vision of Signal was the top three
他对 Signal 的设想是：
to five things you have to get done in
在接下来的 18 小时内，你必须完成的最重要的三到五件事
the next 18 hours. Not your vision for
。 不是你对
the business next week or next month or
公司下周、下个月或
next year. Just the next 18 hours you're
明年的规划。 接下来的18个小时你都
awake. You're going to get those three
醒着。 你要完成你认为对完成任务至关重要的三
things or those five things done that
件或五件事
mission. They must get done today.
。 他们今天必须完成这项工作。
Anything that stops you from doing that
任何阻碍你做这件事的事物都是
is the noise.
噪音。
So this signal to noise ratio to be
所以，
successful for Steve Jobs was 8020. 80
史蒂夫·乔布斯认为成功的信噪比是 8020，即 80 个
signal, 20 noise. And I knew that to be
信号，20 个噪声。 我知道
true with him because he would email me
他就是这样，因为他会
at 2:30 in the morning expect me to get
在凌晨 2:30 给我发邮件，希望我能
back to him because back then we didn't
回复他，因为那时候我们还没有
have texts. It was all email.
短信。 全部都是电子邮件。
He was right. He was right. And the only
他说得对。 他说得对。
other person that I've seen that has a
我见过的唯一一个
higher ratio than that
比例比他更高的人
is Elon Musk. He has no noise. He does
就是埃隆·马斯克。 他没有声音。 他
not deal with noise. He is 100% signal.
不处理噪音。 他是100%信号。
24 seconds of, you know, every cycle. I
你知道，每个循环持续24秒。 我的
mean, the guy is just 60 seconds of
意思是，这个人
every minute, 60 minutes of every hour.
每分钟只占 60 秒，每小时只占 60 分钟。
The 18 hours he's awake, it's all
他醒着的18个小时，全是
signal. And look what he's achieved.
信号。 看看他取得了怎样的成就。
Now, it's very awkward for him socially.
现在，他在社交方面感到非常尴尬。
Because noise is dealing with your
因为噪音有时是和家人相处，有时
family sometimes or noise is saying hi
是
to a friend or noise is is is listening
和朋友打招呼，有时是听
to some doom scrolling on you know some
一些让人沮丧的内容，有时是在
social media app that just takes your
社交媒体应用上漫无目的地浏览，有时是
mind or maybe playing your guitar but
弹吉他，但
very few people on earth and if you go
地球上很少有人，如果你
back in history you're going to find out
回顾历史，你会发现
that the geniuses of their time we're
他们那个时代的杰出人物几乎
close to 100% signal
100%专注于信号。
and so I can really sort of summarize
所以我可以总结一下，
this for my audience signal is the most
信号是
urgent thing you should be focused on
你现在最应该关注的事情，
right now and noise is bas basically
而噪音基本上就是
everything.
一切。
No. The goals you set for that the the
不。你设定的目标，以及
weight the that you were awake if you're
你保持清醒的时间（如果你要
going to be awake 18 hours.
醒着18个小时），都取决于你设定的体重。   是的
Yeah.
。
And you've determined that there's three
你已经确定了有三
things you have to get done. You're
件事必须完成。 你肯定
going to get those done. No matter what
能把那些事做完。 无论付出什么代价
it takes, you're going to get those
，你都要把这些事情
done. And you're not going to let
完成。 你不会让
anything distract you from those three
任何事情分散你对这三
to five things. If you're a CEO and you
到五件事的注意力。 如果你是一位首席执行官，并且能够
achieve that and you can get those done
做到这一点，并且能够
with 80% of your time based on that,
用 80% 的时间完成这些工作，那么
you're extraordinarily successful. You
你就非常成功了。 你
are absolutely and you're Steve Jobs or
绝对是，你是史蒂夫·乔布斯，或者
you're an Elon Musk or you're somebody
你是埃隆·马斯克，或者你是某个人。
if you if you even talk to Bezos I don't
如果你和贝佐斯聊聊，我虽然不
know him personally but I've heard in
认识他本人，但我从
many interviews like I knew you know
很多采访中都听到过类似的说法。我
I've I've met Elon just a few times I
见过埃隆几次，也
spent a lot of time with Jobs but they
和乔布斯相处过很长时间，但他们
say the same thing Bezos will not make a
都说同样的话：贝佐斯
decision after 1:00 in the afternoon
下午一点以后不会做决定，
because he felt that the noise was too
因为他觉得那时的噪音太大，
high the signal for him was in the
对他来说，关键信号是在
morning hours it this is a crucial
早上。我现在明白，这是
aspect of success
成功的关键因素，也是
entrepreneur. A man or woman that
企业家应具备的能力。
understands a signal noise ratio that
懂得信噪比并
focuses on that, they'll be successful.
专注于此的人，将会获得成功。
The ones that can't that get down to a
那些无法将
50/50 signal noise, they'll fail. It's
信号噪声降低到 50/50 的设备，就会失败。 就
that simple. And it's a very simple
这么简单。 这是一个非常简单的
concept.
概念。
You know, you made one of your things
你知道吗，你今天做的一件事就是
today this interview. You're going to
这次采访。 你肯定能
get it done. You're going to all these
完成这件事。 你要去见
people around and everything else. This
周围的所有人，还要处理其他所有事情。 这
is one of the three to five things
是你要完成的三到五件事之一
you're going to get done. I have five
。 我今天有五
things today. I'm going to get them
件事要做。 我会把它们
done. I'll do the same thing tomorrow
完成的。 明天和后天我都会做同样的事情
and the day after that. And you have to
。 你必须
decide how much signal you need to get
决定需要多少信号才能
those three to five things done. And for
完成这三到五件事。
jobs it was 80%.
就业方面，这一比例为 80%。
What's the opposite of that? Sometimes
它的反义词是什么？ 有时，从
looking at the opposite helps us to
反面角度看待问题能帮助我们
understand something. So the opposite of
理解某些事情。 所以，与此相反的是，
I hire managers and CEOs that have a
我雇佣的经理和CEO们
balance in life between the discipline
在生活中保持着平衡，既要兼顾
the binary aspect of business which is I
商业的纪律和二元性（即赚钱和赔钱），又要兼顾
the arts or some other pursuit dance
艺术或其他追求的混乱，比如舞蹈、
painting photography collecting crystals
绘画、摄影、收集水晶
whatever it is that that they that they
等等。他们
have that balance you you need you need
拥有那种平衡，而你需要的是
the ying and yang in your mind to make
头脑中的阴阳平衡，才能做出
correct decisions. It doesn't mean it
正确的决定。 但这并不意味着它
takes you off the signal. The signal is
会让你失去信号。 信号是：
you got to get stuff done. But how do
你得把事情做完了。 但
you live your life? And so I spend a
你如何生活？ 所以我花了
fair amount of my time practicing my
很多时间练习
guitar or working with my photography or
吉他、摄影或者摆弄我的
my my watch, you know, up tonight, very
手表。你知道，今晚
late tonight, I will meet a master watch
很晚的时候，我会见一位制表大师，
maker and we will deal with the design
我们会讨论
of a new piece unique he's going to make
他要为我制作的一件独一无二的新表的设计，
for me and I'm going to love that
我非常期待那
moment. That's going to be something
一刻。 那将和
completely different to what I did all
我一整天所做的事情完全不同
day long. And we'll start our journey
。
together over the next two years to make
接下来两年，我们将携手合作，共同打造一件
this piece unique. And that's something
独一无二的作品。 这让
that just takes me away from all the
我暂时忘却
[__] I'm going to be dealing with today.
今天要面对的所有烦心事。
And I also tell successful entrepreneurs
我还告诉成功的企业家，
in the same day you will get a and this
在同一天你就会得到一个，而
happened to me today. It happens every
今天我就遇到了这种情况。 这种事每天都在发生
day. You're going to get a call from
。 你会接到
some aspect of of your what you you call
你所谓的“帝国”（或者随便你怎么称呼它）某个部门打来的电话，告诉你
your this company's going bankrupt. It's
这家公司要破产了。 它肯定会
just going to go bankrupt and you're
破产，你会
I don't know 10 million bucks on that
在那笔交易中损失1000万美元
deal.
。
And that's a piece of information you're
这就是你现在需要
dealing with. Half an hour later, this
处理的信息之一。 半小时后，
actually happened to me today.
今天这件事竟然真的发生在了我身上。
One of my companies going public. It's a
我的一家公司即将上市。
450x for me.
对我来说是 450 倍。
The stock will get unlocked sometime in
这支股票将于秋季某个时候解锁交易
the fall. But
。 但是，
how can how do you how do you fit that
你该如何将它们结合起来呢
together? Utter catastrophe,
？ 彻底的灾难、
destruction, woe, loss, utter euphoria.
毁灭、悲痛、损失、彻底的狂喜。
half an hour later. That's
半小时后。 这就是
that's what my life is like.
我的生活。
different scale for most founders.
对于大多数创始人来说，这显然是不同规模的创业。
Well, the founders deal with the same
其实，创始人们面临的也是同样的
thing. They get disastrous news. They
问题。 他们收到了灾难性的消息。
something if it's consumer goods or
如果账户是消费品或
service and they get something else. The
服务，他们就会像在 Costco 那样失去账户，然后换成其他东西。
the the eb and flow is is the management
潮起潮落的关键在于管理
of expectations and your ability
预期，以及你应对
emotionally to navigate those ups and
这些起伏跌宕的情绪能力，而这正是
downs is part of what entrepreneurship
创业精神的一部分
is. But it goes back to the signal. It
。 但这一切又回到了信号的问题上。 它
can't take you off the signal. This is
不会让你失去信号。 这是
what Steve taught me. Yes, it's great
史蒂夫教我的。 是的，这是个好
news. Yes, it's bad news. But focus on
消息。 是的，这是个坏消息。 但请集中注意力在
the signal, O Liy. Focus on the signal.
信号上，O Liy。 专注于信号。   就是这样。
Where does this analogy come from of
这种
signal and noise?
信号与噪声的类比源自何处？
It was his genius of of of making it so
他的天才之处在于能把事情变得如此
simple. What are the three things you
简单。 你今天必须完成的三件事是什么
got to get done today? What are they?
？ 这些是什么？
What are they?
这些是什么？
How do you know what they are?
你怎么知道它们是什么？
They will make themselves apparent. They
他们会现身的。 他们
will definitely make themselves
一定会现身的
apparent. They will make themselves
。 他们会
apparent and you will realize I have to
现身的，到那时你就会意识到我必须
deal with that. You may have them set up
处理这件事。 你可能
from the day before. I actually still
前一天就已经把它们设置好了。 我其实现在还在
use sticky notes on my mirror. Got to
镜子上贴便利贴。 必须
get these three things done and or five
完成这三件事，或者五件事，不管是什么
whatever it is. But then something else
。 但随后又会有其他事情
will hit. That's the skill of
发生。 关键在于
understanding is that noise hitting me
理解，那究竟是噪音
or is that signal? There is the essence
还是信号？ 这就是
of the great entrepreneur, the great
伟大企业家、伟大
manager, the great leader. Is that
管理者、伟大领导者的精髓所在。 这是
signal or is that noise? What is it?
信号还是噪音？ 那是什么？
That's what you're looking for. You're
这就是你要找的。 你
hiring somebody that can actually
雇佣的是一个能够真正
distinguish signal and noise because it
区分信号和噪声的人，因为它
could be noise. It could be irrelevant.
可能是噪声。 这可能无关紧要。
You have to determine only you makes
你必须自己做出
that decision. That's the key right
决定。 这就是关键所在
there. This is what I teach
。 这就是我教给
entrepreneurs and engineers and
创业者和工程师的内容，也是
this is the most important thing. It's
最重要的一点。 关键在于对
that judgment of prioritization but then
优先事项的判断，以及
the sort of force of execution to get it
完成任务的执行力
done.
。
Can you interpret signal and noise and
你能分辨信号和噪声吗？
can you keep the noise away from from
你能排除噪声干扰，专注于
the things you got to get done? That's
你需要完成的事情吗？ 这是其中
one. The other which is something that
之一。 另一点是
I've learned over the last 5 years
我在过去 5 年里学到的，
and this uh you might find this
嗯，你可能会觉得这很
interesting but most of my particularly
有趣，但我的大多数，特别是
the naent startups and you're you're
那些初创公司，你
involved in the same format I am. You're
参与的形式和我一样。 你是
dragon stand in England. I'm a shark
英国的龙。 我
tank in the US.
在美国就像一个鲨鱼池。
I you know you put up 500,000 or a
你知道，如果你往别人的公司里投了50万或100
million bucks into somebody's business
万美元，
eight out of 10 is going to fail maybe
十个里有八个会失败，也许
six out of 10 depend you just don't know
六个，这取决于情况，你根本无法预知。我最讨厌
and I love it when people tell me oh I I
别人跟我说“我
know when I make an investment it's
知道我投资肯定会成功”，他们简直
so full of [__] they have I'm talking
胡说八道。我说的是
about startups they have no idea what's
创业公司，他们根本不知道什么会
going to work and you won't know for 5
成功，而且你五
to seven years which is why you need
到七年内都无法知道结果，所以你需要
divers diversification in the portfolio.
投资组合多元化。
But
但
I would go as far to say now, you know,
我现在甚至可以说，你知道，
when I meet um venture capital firms and
当我遇到风险投资公司和在
young analysts that work there and they
那里工作的年轻分析师时，他们都
think they're so damn smart. They've
觉得自己非常聪明。 他们
never operated a business, they know
从未经营过企业，他们什么都不懂
nothing. They have no idea what they're
。 他们根本不知道自己在
doing. They're going to hope that one or
做什么。 他们希望七年后，
two of their portfolio uh is going to
他们投资组合中的一两项投资能够
work out in seven years and pay for all
成功，从而弥补
the other mistakes. But the
其他所有错误。 但
entrepreneurship is brutal. It is. So
创业成功的偶然性是残酷的。 这是。 所以，这是否
that does that mean though that it's I
意味着，
guess I was going to say does that not
我原本想说的是，这是否
mean that it's highly luck? Investing is
意味着很大程度上取决于运气？ 投资与
highly like entrepreneurship must be
创业非常相似，必须……嗯，
well I said karma you know I call it
我说过因果报应，你知道，我称之为因果报应，
karma but you need executional skills
但你需要执行力，
but here's another skill that I think we
但这里还有一项技能，我认为我们
should talk about um
应该谈谈。嗯，
when you look at at least my experience
至少看看我几
over decades of making these
十年来在
uh naent these early stage investments
早期阶段进行的投资经验，
these around investments remarkably and
这些投资非常出色，而且
I've done them in all 11 sectors of the
我在所有11个经济领域都做过，
successes five to seven years later are
五到七年后，大多数成功的
companies run by women. Why is that? Why
公司都是由女性经营的。 这是为什么？ 这
is that?
是为什么？
And so they don't know each other.
所以他们彼此并不认识。
They're in different sectors. They never
他们身处不同的行业。 他们从未
meet each other. Why is that? And I have
见过面。 这是为什么？ 我得出了
two things. They set goals that they can
两个结论。 他们设定自己能够
achieve so that in the early stage of
实现的目标，因此在
their businesses, they put growth rate
创业初期，他们的增长率
targets like 15 16% versus men at 30%.
目标设定为 15% 到 16%，而男性则设定为 30%。
Very often men hit their targets 65% of
男性通常有 65% 的命中率
the time. at least my portfolio and
。 至少我的投资组合和
women 90 [__] plus percent of the time
女性90%以上的时间都在发生性关系，
and that keeps the the the team very
这使得团队非常
sticky. They want to be part of a so
团结。 他们希望成为其中的一份子，这样在公司
they're small. They don't lose the head
规模较小时就不会出现人员流失。 他们并没有失去
of financing and marketing that that
财务和营销方面的领导才能，
works but they have another attribute
但他们还有另一个特点，
and this was pointed out to me by one of
这是
my female CEOs a few years ago to me.
几年前我的一位女CEO向我指出的。
She said, you know, Kevin, you talk too
她说：“凯文，你知道吗，你话太多了
much. You talk too much. Um you talk
。” 你话太多了。 嗯，你说了
two/3s, you listen one third. Why don't
三分之二，听了三分之一。 为什么不
you try reversing the ratio?
试试反过来呢？
She said that to you.
她跟你说过这话。   是的
Yeah. Yeah.
。 是的。
[Laughter]
[笑声]
I'm very thankful actually because I
我其实很感激，因为我
tried it and um she's right. If you
试过了，嗯，她说得对。 如果你
don't talk and you listen, you become
不说话而倾听，你
far more effective as a manager or an
作为管理者或
investor in my case by getting
投资者（就我而言）的效率会大大提高，因为你可以获得那些
information that you weren't going to
你
get by talking. And so if you go into a
通过说话无法获得的信息。 所以，如果你走进一个
room,
房间，就像我
I just did this a few minutes ago before
几分钟前来这里之前做的那样
I came here. I'm involved in a
。 我卷入了一场
litigation and we decided to attempt
诉讼，我们决定尝试
settlement talks which is why I was a
和解谈判，所以我
few minutes late and um
迟到了几分钟。
you know we knew we were going in there
你知道，我们知道我们去那里是为了
to settle and it it's long protruded you
和解，而且这场诉讼旷日持久，你
know long it's a long long long
知道，非常非常漫长。
and I remembered her as we sat at the
当我们像这样坐在桌旁时，我想起了她。
in the room but the two uh you know were
房间里还有其他人，但我们俩面对面坐着
across from each other. I just looked at
。 我只是看了
him. I understand
他一眼。 我明白很久
a long time. And it gets uncomfortable
很久了。 气氛变得很尴尬，
and no one else is talking,
而且其他人都不说话，
you know, just looking.
只是看着。
And um
嗯，
maybe after 90 seconds, he blurted out
大概过了90秒，他脱口而出了
something he shouldn't have said.
一些不该说的话。
And I knew exactly what the price was
我当时就清楚地知道价格是多少
right there.
。   事情就此
That was the end of it.
结束了。
You learned that as a podcaster.
你是通过播客工作学到这一点的。
You learned that there's actually
你发现，
something going on in the silence.
寂静之中其实蕴藏着一些故事。
There is something going on in silence.
寂静之中，暗流涌动。
And it's it's it's the number that he
而这正是他最终决定接受的数字
was going to settle at.
。
He showed his hand.
他亮出了底牌。
So, we saved ourselves two hours. You
这样，我们节省了两个小时。 你
know, it's a it's an attribute that many
知道，这是很多
people can't do because they can't stand
人都做不到的品质，因为他们无法忍受由此带来的
the social uncomfort of it. I have no
社交不适。 我
problem with it. I could sit here and
对此没有异议。 我可以坐在这里
look at you for 10 minutes. it wouldn't
看着你十分钟。
matter to me. And I've actually found it
对我来说无所谓。 我发现这确实
to be a very useful piece of
是一条非常有用的
information. It's not just a
信息。 这不仅仅是
negotiating, but to listen to employees,
谈判，而是要倾听员工、
listen to investors, listen to
投资者、
financeers, listen to alternative ideas
融资者的意见，倾听与你不同的想法，
and become more powerful from it.
并从中变得更强大。
You're in the very business of people
你身处的行业就是不断有人
selling to you and pitching to you. We
向你推销产品、向你兜售商品。 我们
both sit on a similar show where people
俩主持的节目很相似，都是让人们
come in and pitch to us. You're seeing
来节目里向我们推销产品。 有时一天会看到
at times 10 to 12 pitches a day. So
10 到 12 个投球。 所以，在
last couple of decades now almost this
过去的二十年里，你已经培养出了这种能力，几乎是一种
instinctive spidey sense of when an
本能的蜘蛛感应，能够判断一个
entrepreneur will be successful at least
企业家何时会成功，至少
in the context of securing investment.
在获得投资方面是如此。
What have you come to learn about the
你对成功人士的特质有哪些认识
successful? Is there is there anything
？
comes out onto the carpet in the context
在《
of Shark Tank or Dragon's Den even
创智赢家》或《龙穴》等节目中，当创业者走上红毯时，我们能从中汲取什么经验呢？即使
they need the setup shot of the product
他们需要展示
with the entrepreneur and they have a in
创业者的产品镜头，而且在
our case a steady cam or a jib that
我们的节目中，他们会使用稳定器或摇臂进行
comes down and shoots it. So the the
拍摄。 所以，
stage director,
舞台导演，
Eric, uh is his name. I've worked with
呃，他的名字是埃里克。 我和
him for years. Says to the entrepreneurs
他共事多年。 我对那些
I've never met, usually it's a team or
我从未见过的创业者说，通常来说，创业是一个团队、
it's a family or it's whatever. Three or
一个家庭或者其他什么形式。 三四个人
four, two people, whatever. Hold.
，两个人，随便。 抓住。
Hold. Don't speak. Hold. Hold. Don't
抓住。 不要说话。 抓住。 抓住。
mind the camera coming into your face.
别介意镜头怼到你脸上。
Hold. Hold.
抓住。 抓住。
Maybe for two minutes.
或许只有两分钟。
And I'm right there in front of them.
我就站在他们面前。
I'm 12 feet from them. And I just look
我离他们只有12英尺远。 我只是看着
at them. Not smiling, not blinking, not
它们。 不笑，不眨眼，不
frowning, just looking at them.
皱眉，只是看着他们。   在
And before they say a single word, I
他们开口说话之前，我就
know if they're winners or losers. Just
知道他们是赢家还是输家。 就
like that. And why is that? Why is that?
这样。 这是为什么呢？ 这是为什么？
When? And I'm right probably 99% of the
什么时候？ 我大概有 99% 的
time. Maybe I get it wrong one out of a
时间都是对的。 也许我一百次里会有一次出错
hundred. I doubt it though.
。 但我对此表示怀疑。
You walk in a room, even though you've
你走进一个房间，即使你已经
practiced, you know, you in the context
练习过，你知道，在《
of of Shark Tank, 20 plus cameras, a
创智赢家》的背景下，20 多个摄像头，
billion plus dollars in in the five
超过 10 亿美元的资金，坐在
chairs there. You've been practicing for
那里的五个椅子上。 你练习
months your pitch, but it wasn't the
演讲稿好几个月了，但那并不是
real deal. Here you are, cameras are
真正的演讲。 瞧，摄像机在
rolling, tape is running, you know,
运转，录像机在运行，你知道，
you've only got so many minutes.
你只有这么多时间。
This is your moment. And you're on
这是你的时刻。 你上了
national television. 100 plus million
全国电视台。 超过1亿
people will see you in syndication. It's
人将在电视联播中看到你。
all in your mind. It's all in your mind.
一切都在于你的想法。 一切都在于你的想法。   你一直在想这件事
It's going through your head.
。
Can you project
你能通过
who you are with your eyes and the way
眼神和
you're standing? Can you project your
站姿展现出你的个性吗？ 你能展现出你的
confidence? Are you looking at the
自信吗？ 你是不是在看
ground? Are you looking away from me
地面？ 你是不是
because you can't stand me looking at
因为我直视你却不跟
you? Or do you push back? Or did you
你说话而无法忍受你，所以才把目光移开？ 还是你会反击？ 或者你
say, "I'm gonna I'm gonna stake my aura.
说过，“我要展现我的气场。
I'm gonna stake my ground here. I'm
我要在这里表明我的立场。我
gonna show you I'm ready."
要让你们知道我已经准备好了。”
You see what I'm getting at?
你明白我的意思吗？   是的
Yeah.
。
And I can feel it. I can see that
我能感觉到。 我看得出来
they're ready to do battle. They're
他们已经做好了战斗准备。 他们
ready to answer. They're ready to
准备回答。 他们准备进行
present. They're ready. Ready. Ready.
展示。 他们准备好了。 准备好。 准备好。
Ready. Or they're not. And I've taken
准备好。 或者他们并非如此。 我已经把这个节目
that out of the Shark Tank. I see that
从《创智赢家》（Shark Tank）里撤下来了。 我
every day in life. I see it. So you have
每天都能在生活中看到这一点。 我看到了。 所以你
to learn how to project yourself in
必须学会​​如何在
front of your peers or who's who you
同龄人面前展现自己，或者在
want to you want to lead or teach or if
你想要领导或教导的人面前展现自己，或者如果
you're a general or a preacher
你是一位将军或牧师，
that is maybe
这或许是与生俱来的天赋，
maybe you can learn that I don't know I
或许是可以后天习得的，我不知道，我
don't care but if you don't have it
也不关心，但如果你没有这种能力，
you're going to fail and you're just
你就会失败，甚至在开口说话
before the first word is spoken. And so
之前就已经注定了。 那么
then what has to happen?
接下来会发生什么呢？
Then Eric says, "Go. You're on." And
然后埃里克说：“开始吧，轮到你了。”
everybody's just sitting there looking
所有人都坐在那里看着
at you.
你。
Can you articulate your idea in 90
你能否在90秒或更短的时间内清晰阐述你的想法
seconds or less? Can you whatever props
？ 不管你有什么道具
you have or whatever you're going to
或者你要说什么
say, can I get the big idea right away?
，你能马上告诉我你的主要意思吗？
The ones that had that aura generally
那些拥有那种气场的人通常都能成功
get there. 30 seconds later, I get it. I
。  30秒后，我明白了。 我
get what they're here for. I understand
明白他们来这里的目的。 我了解
their product. Okay, that's good.
他们的产品。 好的，那就好。
Unfortunately, great ideas are a dime a
可惜的是，好点子
dozen. I mean, there's millions of them.
比比皆是。 我的意思是，它们有数百万个。
The next phase begins. This is after 90
下一阶段开始。 这是90
seconds. Can you explain why you're the
秒后的情况。 你能解释一下为什么你是
right person to execute on this idea and
执行这个想法并将其
create a business from it? Because you
转化为商业计划的合适人选吗？ 因为你
know something about this space? You
对这个领域有所了解？ 你
worked for a competitor. You've tried
曾为竞争对手工作过。 你
three times before and failed. You
之前尝试过三次都失败了。 你已经
figured out what you did wrong. What is
弄清楚自己错在哪里了。
it about you or your team that can take
你或你的团队具备哪些特质，能够将
this
这个
idea and make it happen? Now, when you
想法变成现实？ 现在，当
get those two things together, you can
这两件事结合在一起时，你就能
feel the aura of the room. The isotope
感受到房间里的氛围了。 同位素之所以引起
is sizzling because you've derisked a
轰动，是因为你降低了一个
great idea. You got an operator in and
绝妙想法的风险。 你派了一名操作员进去，但
they But then the third thing, this is
他们……但是第三件事，这才是
the killer. This is the killer. I've
致命的。 这就是凶手。 我
seen it so many times in real life and
在现实生活中见过太多次这种情况了，简直就是
Shark Tanks real life it is. it.
现实版的《创智赢家》。 它。
You got to know your numbers. How big is
你必须了解你的数据。
the market? How fast is it growing?
市场规模有多大？ 它的增长速度有多快？
What's the gross margin? I mean, I've
毛利率是多少？ 我的意思是，我已经
said this a million times to people. I
跟别人说过无数遍了。 我
teach this every day. How many
每天都教这个。 有多少家
competitors are there? When are you
竞争对手？ 你什么时候才能实现
going to break even? What month? If you
收支平衡？ 几月？ 如果你
get the first two right and you don't
答对了前两题，却不
know your numbers, you deserve to burn
知道你的数字，那你活该
in hell. And I'll put you there myself.
下地狱。 我会亲自把你送到那里。
I mean, you wasted an opportunity for an
我的意思是，你浪费了一个机会，一个真正
entrepreneur that did know their numbers
了解自身财务状况的企业家本来可以抓住这个机会，而
that could have been in that spot that I
我本来
could have invested in. You don't know
可以投资他的。你根本不了解
your numbers. I take you out behind the
自己的财务状况。 我把你带到
barn and shoot you. You should have
谷仓后面，然后开枪打死你。 你应该
brought somebody that understands the
带一个懂
language of business because those three
商业语言的人来，因为这三个人
together are the definition of
加起来就是领导力的定义
leadership right there.
。
I've never heard someone talk about aura
我从未听人这样谈论过
in entrepreneurship quite like that. And
创业中的“气场”。
I was I was just trying to for the
我当时只是想对那些正在
people listening that are either trying
收听的人说，他们要么正在努力
to figure out if they have an aura or to
弄清楚自己是否有气场，要么正在努力
grow that aura. What does it what does
增强自己的气场。 它的
it look and feel like? Is it physically?
外观和触感是什么样的？ 是物理上的吗？
Is it shoulders back? Is it you said
是挺直肩膀吗？ 你说的
it's eye contact? Or is it
是眼神交流吗？ 或者，它根本
indescribable? And do you think you
无法描述？ 你认为你
could take someone who doesn't have that
能教会一个
aura in business and teach them it? Does
在商业上没有那种气场的人吗？
business give you that aura?
商业能给你带来那种光环吗？
I think you can teach it. I certainly
我认为你可以教它。 我一定会
try and teach it to my children. Um I
尽力教给我的孩子们。 嗯，我
try and teach it to my students.
尽量教给我的学生。
And the best way to do it is to look at
最好的办法就是找个
yourself in the mirror sometime. You
时间照照镜子。 你心里觉得
yourself? You know, if you're going to
自己长什么样？ 你知道，如果你要去
go make a presentation to take down a
申请一笔
million-doll line of credit or
百万美元的信贷额度之
something, you want to dress the part,
类的，你当然要穿得体面些，
obviously, but you're going to walk in a
但你走进一个
room with, you know, a loan officer and
房间，里面可能有一位贷款专员，
maybe an assistant, maybe one other,
可能还有一位助理，或者其他一个人，这
depending on the size of the deal, and
取决于交易的规模，
they'll have never met you probably, and
他们可能从未见过你，
you're going to have to project yourself
你必须在
in those seconds as you're walking up to
走上前去和他们握手的那几秒钟内展现出自己的形象。
What does that take? It takes an aura of
这需要什么条件？ 这需要一种自信的气质
confidence. And it's in the eyes. It's
。 一切都体现在眼神里。
in the way you're you're standing. It's
关键在于你的站姿。 关键在于
in how the way you're dressed. It's it's
你的穿着打扮。
you know. It's it's um
你知道，穿着得体可不是开玩笑的。 嗯，这其实是
but it's it's something about presenting
关于如何展现
yourself and keeping your eyes focused
自己，如何将目光集中
on who's talking to you so that they
在与你交谈的人身上，让他们
know that you're absorbing the
知道你在吸收
information, that you respect the
信息，你尊重
information, that you're about to get
信息，你即将
into a narrative with them of respect
与他们进行一场尊重的对话，
even though that there may be
即使可能存在
disagreements. All of this is happening
分歧。 这一切都发生
in the first 60 seconds. And it's
在最初的60秒内。 这为
setting up for the rest of your life
你们余生
with that person. It could be who you're
与对方的相处奠定了基础。 这可能就是你
going to marry. It could be who you're
未来的伴侣。 这可能与你
going to work with. It could be your
未来的工作伙伴有关。 它可能是你的
partner in business. It could be your
商业伙伴。 可能是你的
banker. It could be anybody. It could be
银行家。 可能是任何人。 他可能是会为
life for you. It's sort of who are you?
你献出生命的士兵。 这有点像是在问：你是谁？   就是这样。
Just closing off on the point you made
最后我想补充一点，你提到
about women being your most successful
女性是你最成功的
investments and the companies that have
投资对象，而且给
given you the greatest returns tend to
你带来最大回报的公司往往是由
led by women. Does that mean that you
女性领导的。 这是否意味着你们会
focus on hiring women into executive
重点招聘女性担任高管
roles?
职位？
Yeah, I'm practically all women. Um,
是的，我几乎全是女性角色。 嗯，
particularly Asian women. I am a uh, you
尤其是亚洲女性。 我，你
know, this whole thing about DEI and all
知道，就是关于多元化、公平和包容（DEI）以及所有这些
this stuff. I've always had diversity
东西。 我一直以来都注重多元化，
because I only hire on merit. I don't
因为我只择优录用。 我
care if what sex you are or what you
不在乎你的性别、你的
call yourself or what where you came
自称、你的出身、
from or the color of your skin or what
你的肤色，或者
planet you were born on. I couldn't give
你出生在哪个星球。 我根本不在乎
a [__] Can you execute?
。 你能执行吗？
And the way I hire people, and that's
而我招聘员工的方式，也是我
operating company, I don't hire you. I
运营公司拥有如此多元化员工队伍的原因，就是我不会雇用你。 我会
say, "Look, you sound good, and you look
说：“听着，你听起来不错，
great on paper, but that doesn't mean
简历也很好，但
anything if you can't work within the
如果你不能融入
team. So, I know you want a job and you
团队，这一切都毫无意义。我知道你想要一份工作，
want benefits and all that stuff, but
想要福利什么的，但
I'm not going to do that. If you want to
我不会给你这些。如果你想
be part of my universe, you're going to
成为我团队的一员，你将以
contractor at a much higher salary.
合同工的身份工作四到六个月，薪水会高得多。
because you're not going to get any
因为你不会获得任何
stock options, you're not going to get
股票期权，也不会有
any uh benefits. But I just want to see
任何福利。我只是想看看
what it's like for you to work with all
你和
of the people that we deal with every
我们每天接触的所有人一起工作是什么感觉
day. All the lawyers, all the bankers,
。所有的律师、银行家、
all of the, you know, the CEOs that we
我们投资的所有CEO，
have investments in and and your
还有你的
co-workers because I don't do 9 to5
同事，因为我现在不朝九晚五了
anymore. I do projectbased work. I don't
。我做的是项目制工作。我
care where you live. We have people
不在乎你住在哪里。我们
working in Dubai, Abu Dhabi, uh England.
在迪拜、阿布扎比、英国都有人工作。
I mean, everywhere. everywhere and and
我的意思是，到处都有。到处都有。
you know we meet we try and find an hour
我们会见面，尽量每周抽出一个小时，让
every week where we can see each other
每个人都能见一见。”
but we're just constantly communicating
虽然我们
using modern day tools today but
现在一直在使用现代工具进行沟通，但
you know can you actually be given a
你知道，关键在于你是否真的能被赋予
mandate and execute on it that's it I
任务并执行它。我
don't care when you do it if you have to
不在乎你什么时候完成，比如说，如果你负责
get the financials out let's say you're
财务工作，
running in finance you got to get them
你必须在15号之前完成财务报表以缴纳
out the 15th for taxes I don't care when
税款，我不在乎你什么时候
you do it but if you miss the 15th I
完成，但如果你错过了15号，我会很
care so I I need to find out if those
在意。所以我需要了解这些
people can fit into that kind of an
人是否能适应这种
environment. Some of them make it, some
环境。有些人能适应，有些
of them don't. Some sometimes we know
人则不行。有时候，
right away after 90 days, let's hire
90天后我们就能立刻判断出他们是否合适，我们会聘用
them, bring them in the team, and you
他们，让他们加入团队，并
know, let's give them the whole package.
提供全套福利。
And sometimes after a month, we say,
但有时候，一个月后，我们会说：
"No, it's not going to work. Here's
“不行，这行不通。” 就是这样
like, you know, that's it." I think I
，你知道，就是这样。” 我
think more companies should do that.
觉得更多公司应该这样做。
Actually, it's more like the Swiss
实际上，这更像是瑞士的
apprentice system. They bring you into a
学徒制度。他们会把你带入一个
lot like, you know, my stepfather's
很……你知道，我继父是
Swiss. I've been going to Switzerland
瑞士人。我去瑞士已经
for 50 years. So if you're a giant
50年了。所以，如果你是一家
company like a Fiser or a Nestle, you
像菲仕或雀巢这样的大公司，你
pull them out of high school at 14. You
会把14岁的高中生招进来。你
give them a job in the afternoon. They
给他们安排下午的工作。他们
become an apprentice. They want to
成为学徒。他们渴望
learn. They want to work. They want to
学习。他们渴望工作。他们渴望
understand what it's like and then you
了解工作是什么样的，然后你在
find the the winners at while they're
他们还在上高中的时候就找到那些优秀的人
still in high school. Then you give them
。然后你给他们
summer jobs and then you bring them into
暑期工，最后把他们招进
the company. That's where I got the idea
公司。我的想法就是从这里来的
from. The Swiss are genius that way
。瑞士人在这方面很聪明，
because you're sort of mitigating the
因为他们在某种程度上降低了
risk. I guess you're taking less of a a
风险。我想你承担的风险更小
risk on No, but you're also finding out
，但你也在了解
if their their DNA is going to fit with
他们的基因是否适合
your I mean, I want my team to make a
你的……我的意思是，我希望我的团队赚
ton of money. I I just I want them to be
很多钱。我只是…… 让他们
successful. I want every person to be
成功。我希望每个人都能为
proud to work with the other and and
与其他人共事而感到自豪，这样
just we're almost invincible. We're so
我们几乎所向披靡。我们
damn good at what we do. You have the
做事真的太棒了。你们
same thing here. You you don't have
这里也是一样。你们没有不
people that don't work for you. Well,
为你们效力的人。好吧，
you get rid of them. You whack them. I'm
那就解雇他们。干掉他们。我的做法
more just formal about it. Boom. You're
更正式一些。砰！你
gone.
就走了。
With with the investments that you've
就你
made, how many investments How many
做过的投资而言，你在《创智赢家》（
offers have you done on Shark Tank now?
Shark Tank）节目中做了多少投资？
probably like 800
大概有800个吧，
we know we don't even count it anymore
我们现在都不数了，
we look at the portfolio rolling over a
我们看的是过去
5 to sevenyear period
5到7年投资组合的滚动情况，真的
a lot like a lot and and the thing is
很多。关键是，
the thing what I've learned is you get a
我学到的是，你会得到一个
you get an exit like uh base pause from
退出机会，比如
five years ago or something
五年前的某个项目，或者更久。那位
remarkable woman
了不起的女性，
that was the the cat DNA thing
就是那个
the cat DNA thing I mean nobody saw that
猫DNA项目，我的意思是，没人预料到会是这样，我当时
coming I thought the thing was a joke um
以为那是个玩笑，嗯，
I was so wrong I mean that's the whole
我大错特错了，我的意思是，这就是关键所在。
point and and She she had the highest
而且，她拥有
IRA I think in the whole format's
整个节目历史上最高的个人退休账户（IRA）
history. Nobody's made her She was
。 没人能让她成功。她存在了
around for 36 months and taken out at
36个月，而且是以极其
such an extreme number in all cash that
惊人的价格全款现金收购的，以至于
there was an NDA signed between Sony and
索尼和那家制药公司之间签署了保密协议
the the pharmaceutical company. I can't
。我甚至不能
even tell you what it was. It was
告诉你具体金额是多少。简直
extraordinary. It was extraordinary.
不可思议。真的不可思议。
Was it nine figures?
是九位数吗？
Believe me, it's a tough NDA because and
相信我，那份保密协议非常苛刻，因为
I understand why they did it. They
我理解他们为什么这么做。他们
didn't buy it for the cat DNA testing.
收购这家公司不是为了猫的DNA检测。
They bought it for the data
他们是为了
with AI didn't really wasn't emerging
人工智能数据，当时人工智能还没有真正兴起
then. It existed but it wasn't with the
。它虽然存在，但远不及
data they have now. They can develop
现在的数据量。他们可以利用这些数据开发出
extraordinary in terms of feeds and
在饲料和药物方面都非常出色的动物产品
medicines.
。
Yeah.
是的。
And nobody had that much data on the 110
而且没有人拥有美国1.1亿只猫的如此庞大的数据，
million cats in America because she got
因为她是
it all during the pandemic. thousands
在疫情期间获得这些数据的。
and thousands and thousands of of of you
成千上万只猫，你
know it was it was never about it was it
知道，这从来就不是一家公司，它
was a data company. It's like my son
是一家数据公司。这就像我儿子在
Tesla, "Hey dad, it's not a car company.
特斯拉实习时告诉我，“嘿，爸爸，这不是一家汽车公司。”
It's a data company."
这是一家数据公司。”
Buy the stock. I said, "I'm never buying
买入股票。我说：“我永远不会买
the stock. It's a joke. It's so
这支股票。” 这只是个玩笑。  “
expensive." He said, "You're an idiot.
太贵了。”他说，“你真是个白痴。”   “
It's not a car company." So I bought the
它不是一家汽车公司。”所以我买了特斯拉的
stock and he was right. It became my
股票，他说得对。这成了我
most successful investment. I I had to
最成功的投资。我不得不
keep selling it down to 5%. My cost base
不断卖出，直到持股比例降到5%。
is zero on Tesla now.
现在我在特斯拉的投资成本是零。真是
[__] hell.
见鬼了。
Yeah. Before it split and he worked
是的。在特斯拉分拆之前，他在
there for 5 years.
那里工作了5年。
One of the personas that I have that
我认识的
lot. You know, they they come up to me
很多看我节目的人都是年轻人，不一定是年轻人，但他们经常坐在沙发上想着创业，而且经常谈论这个。你知道，他们会在街上走过来跟我说：“
Twothirds will never do it.
三分之二的人永远不会去做。
That you you might as well do it when
你最好等到
you have less burdensome risk like a
风险负担减轻一些的时候再去，比如
mortgage in a family. You might as well
家里有房贷的时候。你最好
do it in your 20s. You're going to fail
在20多岁的时候就去做。你
the first time, maybe the second, maybe
第一次肯定会失败，第二次可能也会失败，
the third. You only need one success.
第三次也可能失败。你只需要一次成功。”我
You I had plenty of failures and I I
经历过很多失败，现在也
still have failures. I mean, it's just,
还在经历失败。我的意思是，
you know, that one I talked about this
你知道，就像我今天
morning. It's, you know, when I I you
早上说的那个。你知道，当我……你
know, I I said to the largest
知道，我对最大的……说……
shareholders as was I was in the car and
当时我在车里，
your assistant was, you know, at looking
你的助理也在车里看着我，你知道的
at me in the limo. I was telling the
。我告诉
other two shareholders, "Listen, guys,
另外两位股东：“听着，伙计们，
it's it's a binary decision. As soon as
这是一个非此即彼的决定。”
I get out of this interview, we're going
我一结束这次面试，我们就会
to make a decision.
做出决定。
This company's going bankrupt." Oh, on
这家公司要破产了。” 哦，关于那家
the bankrupt company.
破产的公司。
Yeah. Yeah. And so if we want to save
是啊，是啊。所以如果我们想拯救它
it, everybody's going to have to pony up
，每个人都得拿出
x million. And um we're going to own the
几百万。然后，我们要
whole thing. We're just going to own it
全盘收购。我们要全盘收购。我们要以每股几分之一美分的价格进行强制融资
cent. We're going to own the whole
。我们要全盘收购。
thing. You want to do that or you want
你们想这么做，还是
to let it go bankrupt? You guys choose.
想让它破产？你们自己选。我持有三分之一的股份。
I'm onethird of it. So it's going to
所以，
have to be, you know, two against one.
你知道，这得是二对一。
And I'll do whatever they want because
我会做他们想做的任何事，因为
that's how I am. But it's, you know, you
我就是这样的人。但是，你知道，你
want to get yourself in a position in
想让自己处于一个
life. I think most CEOs understand this.
有利的位置。我想大多数CEO都明白这一点。
You are going to have bad outcomes.
你会遇到糟糕的结果。肯定会有
There are going to be bad outcomes. But
糟糕的结果。但永远
never put yourself in a situation where
不要让自己陷入一种境地，让
one bad outcome defines who you are. I
一次糟糕的结果定义你是谁。我的
mean, for those shareholders, they're
意思是，对那些股东来说，他们会
going to be unhappy. But then I got the
不高兴。但后来我接到了
call on the IPO. Those shareholders be
IPO的电话。 那些股东肯定
very happy. They're going to make 400
高兴坏了。他们要赚400
400x. So it and that was one of my
倍。这就是我做的其中一笔
deals. And so it's sort of like
交易。所以，这就像
learn to live with the idea that
学会接受
you're going to fail. You're going to
失败的现实。
lose money by taking risk.
承担风险就意味着赔钱。
Will it change relationships
这会永久改变人际关系吗
permanently? Maybe. But if there if
？也许会。但如果
you're respected and you're honest and
你受人尊敬，为人诚实
you're transparent, probably not. I
透明，那可能不会。我
think there's a lot of people don't like
觉得很多人不喜欢我直言不讳。
me for my bluntness. I don't care.
我不在乎。
I think a lot of people respect me for
我觉得很多人尊重我的
my blindness. They may not like me and
直率。他们可能不喜欢我，但
you know it's sort of um it doesn't
你知道，这其实并不
matter because the only people that
重要，因为
really matter to me are probably my
对我来说真正重要的人可能只有我最
20iest closest friends in my family.
亲近的20个家人朋友。
Do you think if you hadn't worked with
你觉得如果你没有和
or known Steve Jobs you would be a
史蒂夫·乔布斯共事或认识他，你会成为
different person?
另一个人吗？
100%. Steve changed my life. There's no
百分之百会。史蒂夫改变了我的人生。毫无
question.
疑问。
I didn't like him. But
我不喜欢他。但
I feel so bad that he he didn't have to
我很遗憾他本不必
die that way.
那样死去。
He just wouldn't go with the modern
他只是不想那样做。
medicine at the time is my view. Guy was
我的看法是，应该遵循当时的现代医学。乔布斯真是
a freaking genius.
个天才。
He was so smart in terms of keeping on
他非常聪明，总能
track to get getting stuff done and look
按部就班地完成任务，看看
what he achieved. But he was
他取得了怎样的成就。但他
difficult
很难相处，
difficult because he wasn't always
因为他并非总是
right. But he was right so much that the
正确的。但他做对的次数太多了，以至于那些
mistakes just didn't matter.
错误根本无关紧要。
And I thought, you know, the people that
我想，那些
spent enough time with him know what I'm
和他相处足够长时间的人都知道我在
talking about. Um,
说什么。嗯，
you know, it occurred to me because I
我之所以想到这一点，是因为我
know Waznjak too, not as well as Jobs,
也认识瓦兹尼亚克，虽然不如乔布斯那么熟，
but they really needed each other. They
但他们彼此非常需要对方。他们
really needed each other because W
真的需要对方，因为瓦兹尼亚克
understood he was he understood what the
明白……
let me draw an analogy here for you. I
让我举个例子。我
think it's a good one.
觉得这个例子很贴切。
take the situation going on right now
就拿现在英
Nvidia, AMD, to a certain extent Intel,
伟达、AMD，某种程度上还有英特尔，
um maybe Broadcom,
嗯，或许还有博通来说，这些公司的情况来说，
where policymakers in Washington have
华盛顿的决策者们
decided that we can't sell those chips
决定我们不能把这些芯片卖给
to countries like China or Russia or
中国、俄罗斯或者
whatever the list is of adversaries.
其他任何敌对国家。
That's bad policy.
这是个糟糕的政策。原因
And here's why. What I learned from
如下。我从
from jobs was
乔布斯身上学到的是，
the the computer, the chip is the queen
计算机，芯片才是核心。
bee. It's it's the it's the queen bee.
蜜蜂。它是，它是，它是蜂后。
But it has no value without the
但如果没有蜜蜂，它就毫无价值。蜜蜂指的是
around it that form a community that
围绕着它的程序员们，他们组成了一个社群，
spend all of their energy
倾尽全力
writing code that works with the queen
编写与蜂后（芯片）兼容的代码，而蜂后正是那颗不断
bee, which is the chip that pushes out
扩张
its influence. Because every coder that
影响力的芯片。因为每一个
becomes familiar with that firmware,
熟悉这套固件、
that Bosnjak computer, writes to that
这台博斯尼亚克计算机、并为该
platform, is part of the honeybees.
平台编写代码的程序员，都是蜜蜂群体的一员。
Jobs understood that. He said, "I've got
乔布斯明白这一点。他说：“我必须
to get every honeybee writing for the
让每一位蜜蜂都为
Mac,
Mac、
writing for the OS of Apple."
为苹果操作系统编写代码。”
the Nvidia chip.
英伟达芯片也是如此。
We need to sell it to everybody. Every
我们需要把它卖给所有人，
even adversaries because within
甚至包括对手，因为在
that country of Russia or China is some
俄罗斯或中国，总会有一些
genius kid. You don't know who he is or
天才少年。你不知道是谁，谁会为
from the queen bee,
蜂后——
the chip, the American queen bee. The
芯片，也就是美国的蜂后——编写下一段固件或高级人工智能。
minute you shut down a market and you
一旦你关闭了一个市场，而你
don't, your adversary sends their queen
没有这样做，你的对手就会派出他们的
bee in, which is Huawei.
蜂后——华为。
We can't let that happen because I don't
我们不能让这种情况发生，因为…… 我不
think the lawmakers understand what jobs
认为立法者们理解乔布斯所
understood. You create the hive with the
理解的。你创造一个蜂巢，
queen in the middle. That's the chip.
蜂后位于中心。那就是芯片。
You convince every bee around
你让周围的每只蜜蜂都
to make the honey, which is the
酿造蜂蜜，蜂蜜就是
software, and that is the AI in this in
软件，在
this case. You make it off that chip.
这个例子中就是人工智能。你从这个芯片中创造一切。
And when you advance the chip, again,
当你推进芯片发展时，
everybody knows how to take that set and
每个人都知道如何利用这套系统，并
stay within the American chip that
保持在
you're advancing.
你正在推进的美国芯片的框架内。
Maybe you keep them one generation
也许你会让他们
behind. Maybe maybe that's the policy.
落后一代。也许这就是政策。
But you don't ever let an adversary put
但你永远不能让对手把
their queen bee in the middle of the
他们的蜂后放在
hive. You see what I'm saying?
蜂巢的中心。你明白我的意思吗？
Of course. I mean,
当然。我的意思是，
and that is what Jobs did. That was the
这就是乔布斯所做的。这就是
war between Gates and Jobs on the OS, on
盖茨和乔布斯之间关于
the operating system.
操作系统的战争。
Yeah. I was thinking about the app store
是的。我想到了应用商店，是的
and yeah,
，情况
it's the same thing. It's exactly the
是一样的。完全一样
same thing. And so, so when I see this
。所以，当我看到
policy now,
现在的这项政策时，
I go out of my mind. I mean, the first
我简直要疯了。我的意思是，
thing I do is get on a plane, go to
我做的第一件事就是飞去
Washington because AI is so important
华盛顿，因为人工智能
for all the investments I've made. I do
对所有投资都至关重要。 我已经决定了。我绝对
not want to be putting Chinese honey
不想
into my companies at all. It's that
在我的公司里放任何中国蜂蜜。就这么
simple. So for that person that's
简单。所以，对于那些正在
stewing over their ideas now, if they
酝酿创业想法的人，如果他们
had just a couple of minutes with you
能和你聊几分钟，
and they and they asked you the
问问你：“
question, Kevin, I'm about to start this
凯文，我即将开始
business. I'm about to go on this
创业，即将踏上这段从零开始的
journey of trying to go from zero to
旅程，努力
something in my life. Is there anything
在人生中有所成就。在
else that I need to know as I set upon
我开启
this sort of next 10 years of my life?
人生下一个十年之际，还有什么需要注意的吗？
I'm 21 years old. What what are because
我今年21岁。” 因为
I think every entrepreneur has like
我认为每个创业者都有
their principles. You you talked about
自己的原则。你刚才提到了
one which is the signal versus noise
信号与噪音的对比
thing. Are there any other foundational
。
principles that you think are conducive
你认为还有哪些其他有助于成功的基本原则是
that you might have learned?
你总结出来的？是的，
Yeah, I mean I what I'm telling 20 21
我现在告诉20到21岁的
year olds now is look,
年轻人，
go work for 24 months in a sector you
去你热爱并充满激情的行业工作24个月
love that you're passionate about. Even
。
if they don't pay you, go in there and
即使他们不付你工资，也要去那里
be an apprentice. Um, if you're that
做学徒。嗯，如果你真的那么
passionate, you're going to be able to
充满热情， 你肯定能
convince some manager to go work for
说服某个经理去
free in there. you're just they're going
那里免费工作。他们会
to recognize your passion and they're
发现你的热情，然后把
going to bring you in. Do that first.
你招进去。先做这件事。
Most young entrepreneurs say, "Nah, nah,
大多数年轻的创业者都会说：“不，不，
I don't want to work for anybody." I
我不想为任何人工作。” 我
said, "Yeah, you do actually. You you do
说：“不，你其实想。” 你确实
want to work for somebody. You want to
想为别人工作。 你
just understand how all the cogs move.
只是想了解所有齿轮是如何运转的。
Just 24 months and after that launch.
仅仅24个月后，就推出了。
The first one will probably fail. You're
第一个很可能会失败。 你
going to start with your parents giving
首先会从父母那里得到
you 10,000 bucks or whatever it is,
1 万美元或者其他什么数额，然后是
friends and family. But you will have
朋友和家人。 但你将具备所在
the baseline knowledge of your industry.
行业的基本知识。
You will know who the participants are.
您将知道参赛者有哪些。
You will understand how it works and
你会明白它的运作原理，
success. But the key is to launch sort
成功的概率也会大大提高。 但关键在于要在二十五六岁的时候开始创业，
because you need to burn a few years
因为你需要经历几年的
failing and and that that matters.
失败，而这很重要。
On the point of how to lead people, when
关于如何领导他人，当
people hear about Jobs's approach, they
人们听到乔布斯的方法时，
sometimes assume that you also have to
有时会认为你也必须
be an [__] And this is the this is
是个混蛋。 这就是
the conflicting thing because the world
矛盾之处，因为自
has changed since Jobs was in a
乔布斯担任
leadership position. Things have gone a
领导职务以来，世界已经发生了变化。
little bit more soft shall one say.
可以说，情况变得稍微缓和了一些。
Have you seen all all types of
你见过各种类型的
leadership win out in that regard? The
领导方式在这方面都取得胜利吗？
direct you know signal focused kind of
你知道，这种直接的信号传递方式既大胆又直接，既有
brash approach but also the kind
鲁莽的一面，也有温和的一面
approach.
。
I don't think kind works. I think
我觉得善良行不通。 我认为
respect works. I I the same number of
尊重是有效的。 现在
[__] are out there being successful
成功人士中的混蛋数量和
now as they were back in the 90s. Um
90 年代一样多。 嗯，
it doesn't matter um whether you're an
你是不是个
[__] or whether people like you or
混蛋，别人喜
not. I mean, people get so stuck on this
不喜欢你，这些都不重要。 我的意思是，人们太执着于这些
stuff. It it's
事情了。 问题在于
the team you're building are not your
你组建的团队里没有你的
friends. They are the team you're
朋友。 他们是你为了
building to execute on a mandate. Your
执行任务而组建的团队。
customers come first. They're more
客户至上。 它们更
important. And then of course the
重要。 当然还有
employees and how are they respected or
员工，以及他们是否受到尊重
not. There are people that work for me I
。 我手下有些员工我
don't like. It doesn't matter. I respect
不喜欢。 没关系。 我尊重
them. I respect their ability to
他们。 我尊重他们的
execute. And that above all is the most
执行能力。 而这才是最
important thing. If you start getting
重要的。 如果你开始
into interpersonal relationships, you
涉足人际关系，你
will fail because you may have to fire
将会失败，因为你总有一天可能不得不解雇
that person one day. People that hire
那个人。 雇用
family take huge risk. Nepotism is a
亲属的人要承担巨大的风险。 裙带关系是一种
horrible disease. It's it's uh some of
可怕的顽疾。 世界上一些最
the greatest uh private companies on
伟大的私营公司从来
earth never let the kids run them. They
不让孩子们来经营它们。 他们
just put them on the board and they hire
只是把这些人列入董事会，然后聘请
professional management. That's how they
专业的管理人员。 这就是他们如何
keep wealth multigenerational.
让财富代代相传的。
Think about a tetropac for example.
例如，想想四方包装。
People may not know that name but it's a
人们可能不熟悉这个名字，但它是一家
massive successful company. IKEA I mean
非常成功的公司。 宜家，我的意思是，
you know it's sort of you have to learn
你知道，你必须吸取
those lessons. It's it's um
这些教训。 这关乎
in both directions. It's not about
双向尊重。 这与
likability or softness or some social
讨人喜欢、性格温和或某些社交
met metric. It it really isn't. And
指标无关。 事实并非如此。
trying to redefine leadership that way
试图通过这种方式重新定义领导力，仅仅
because it's on trend, it's not going to
因为它符合潮流，是
work.
行不通的。
I started my first business at 12 years
我12岁时创办了我的第一家公司，14岁
old and I started more businesses at 14,
、
15, 16, 17, and 18. And at that time,
15岁、16岁、17岁和18岁时我又创办了更多公司。当时，
what I didn't realize is that being a
我没有意识到，作为一名
founder with no money meant that I also
没有资金的创始人，这意味着我还要身兼数职，既是
had to be the marketeteer, the sales
市场营销人员、销售
rep, the finance team, customer service,
代表，又是财务人员、客户服务人员，
and the recruiter. But if you're
还是招聘人员。 但如果你
starting a business today, thankfully,
今天开始创业，值得庆幸的是，
there's a tool that wears all of those
有一个工具可以为你承担所有这些
hats for you, our sponsor today, which
角色，那就是我们今天的赞助商
is Shopify. Because of all of its AI
Shopify。 由于
integrations, using Shopify feels a bit
Shopify 集成了各种人工智能技术，使用 Shopify 感觉就像
from day one, taking care of writing
从一开始就聘请了一个完整的增长团队，负责撰写
product descriptions, your website
产品描述、网站
design, and enhancing your products
设计和优化产品
images. Not to mention the bits you'd
图片。 更不用说那些你
expect Shopify to handle, like the
期望 Shopify 处理的部分了，比如
shipping, like the taxes, like the
发货、税收、
inventory. And if you're looking to get
库存管理等等。 如果您想
your business started, go to
开始创业，请访问
shopify.com/bartlet
shopify.com/bartlet
and sign up for a $1 per month trial.
并注册，即可享受每月 1 美元的试用价。
That's shopify.com/bartlet.
那是 shopify.com/bartlet。
What about finding the definition of the
那么，
word company is group of people. So in
公司这个词的定义是“一群人”吗？ 那么，在
terms of finding great people, is there
寻找优秀人才方面，
anything that you can offer to
您能否为
entrepreneurs that are listening about
正在收听的创业者们提供一些建议，比如
how you've done that and what you've
您是如何找到优秀人才的，以及您在
made with assembling your group of
组建团队的过程中学到了什么，犯了哪些错误
people.
。   是的
Yeah. Hiring them without testing them
。 未经测试就直接录用他们
first. I've made that mistake.
。 我犯过这个错误。
So So you now test them first.
所以，现在你要先测试它们。
Just because someone says they can
仅仅因为某人声称自己能
execute doesn't mean they can. I mean
做到，并不意味着他们真的能做到。 我的意思是，
it's of course you're in an interview.
你当然是在面试。
They're not going to say I can't
他们不会说我不能
execute. You know, you're looking at
执行任务。 你知道，你是在了解
their past. You're saying this looks
他们的过去。 你的意思是说这看起来
terrific. Looks like you can fit in, but
棒极了。 看起来你好像能进去，但这只是纸上的纸而已
it's on a piece of paper. They haven't
。 它们还没有
been road tested. They haven't been put
经过道路测试。 他们还没有被置于
in a situation where they have to make
必须做出会产生后果的
individual decisions that that have
个人决定的境地
consequence. The people you want are
。 你想要的那种人，
able to make decisions that have
能够做出有
consequence. Good, bad, good
后果的决定。 好结果，坏结果，好
consequence, bad consequence. You don't
结果，坏结果。 你现在还不
know yet. But they have to have be able
知道。 但他们必须能够
to make that decision on their own
自己做出决定，而
without calling you up because you gave
无需打电话给你，因为你已经赋予了
them that mandate. Maybe you put a set
他们这项权力。 也许你设定了一组
of parameter you could spend a million
参数，这样你就不用再花一百万
bucks no more without calling me. But
美元而不用打电话给我了。 但
whatever it is, I don't want to hear
不管是什么事，我都不想再听到
from them. I just want the outcome.
他们的消息。 我只想知道结果。
What about resilience and hard work? How
那么韧性和努力呢？
much does that matter to you? Cuz I know
这件事对你来说有多重要？ 因为我知道
you said they can work when you know
你说过，
they as long as they get the job done.
只要他们能把工作完成，他们就能胜任。
But are you trying to figure out if they
但你是不是想弄清楚他们
are a bit of a psychopath in terms of
在努力程度上是否有点精神病态
hard work, if they're possessed,
，或者他们是否被某种力量控制、
obsessed?
痴迷于此？
I don't find the ones that are
我发现那些
psychopaths hard work are actually the
精神变态者，即使不努力，也往往是
most successful. It's not the case. I
最成功的。 事实并非如此。 我
find the ones that are eclectic people
发现那些兴趣广泛、除了自己从事的行业之外还有其他爱好的人，会
do crazy stuff. You know, maybe it's
做一些疯狂的事情。 你知道，也许是
riding motorcycles in the desert. I
在沙漠里骑摩托车。 我
don't know. You know, these are the
不知道。 你知道，
examples I'm just using because I'm
我之所以举这些例子，只是因为我一直在经历这些事
living with them.
。
And say, "Look, I've got to go and ride
然后说：“你看，我得骑
a bicycle across the the desert." Okay.
自行车穿越沙漠。” 好的。
How many days you going to be gone? I
你要离开几天？ 我
don't know. Maybe three. Okay. Is there
不知道。 或许三个。 好的。 有
anything that is immediate? That tells
什么迫在眉睫的事情吗？ 这说明，
if you look at if you look at the years
如果你看看
outcome from that person, you're going
这个人这些年的表现，你会
to find that they probably outperformed.
发现他很可能表现得非常出色。
You you you want you want you want the
你你你想要你你想要你想要那些
eclectic ones. You want the ones that
风格各异的。 你想要的是那些
are not just robots working. It it's
不仅仅是机器人在工作的。
going to be cheaper to get a robot if
如果
you want a robot. I'm going to buy those
你想要一个机器人，那么买一个机器人会更便宜。
too when they come available. But I want
等它们上市后我也打算买一些。 但我想要的是那些
people that have creative
拥有创造性
and
和
unusual solutions
不寻常解决方案的人，那种跳出固有思维模式思考的人
box.
。
It's it's really interesting that way.
这样看来真的很有意思。
The other thing that um everybody wants
大家还
to hear from you about is how to keep
想听你谈谈如何保住
and grow your wealth because you know
和增加财富，因为你知道，
making wealth. I kind of understand
创造财富是一件很困难的事情。
through the lens of entrepreneurship,
从创业的角度来看，我多少能理解：
take a big bet, um hopefully have an
孤注一掷，希望能够成功
exit or you know draw a dividend or make
退出，或者
profit from a company you've started.
从你创办的公司中获得股息或利润。
But in terms of what you did and your
但就你所做的以及你
relationship with your money, what is
与金钱的关系而言，对于
the most important things for someone to
一个
understand who's just trying to grow
只想让
their money?
自己的钱增值的人来说，最重要的是要理解什么？   是的
Yeah. Yeah. Know I learned this from my
。 是的。 我知道这是我从
mother and I actually built a whole
母亲那里学到的，而且
indexing company around it when I was
我年轻的时候还围绕这个主题建立了一家索引公司
very young. I found out something uh
。 我发现了一些事情，嗯，
that um so she um was fiercely
她非常
independent. She's one of three
独立。 她是家中三个
daughters uh of Lebanese descent. Myth's
女儿之一，拥有黎巴嫩血统。  Myth的
father, my my father, my original
父亲，我的父亲，我的亲生
father, biological father was Irish.
父亲，我的生父是爱尔兰人。
She didn't Yeah, there she is. Geette.
她没有。是的，她在那里。 吉特。
I haven't seen that picture in a while.
我已经很久没看到那张照片了。
Okay.
好的。
She was very independent
她非常独立，从来
she never ever wanted a man to control
不希望男人控制
her life. So she started at an early age
她的生活。 所以她很小的时候就开始
when she was working for her father.
帮父亲工作了。
They paid the girls. the family all
他们付钱给女孩们了。 家里所有人都在
worked there and she worked in the
那里工作，她在
accounting department
会计
and billing, but she got paid cash and
和账单部门工作，但她拿的是现金工资，
so she
所以她
of that cash each week and
每周会拿出 20% 的现金，然后
she would put it into two asset classes.
将其投资到两类资产中。
Stocks that paid dividends, large cap
派发股息的股票、大盘
stocks and telco bonds.
股和电信债券。
half to 8% back then. She bought the
当时7年期电信债券的收益率约为6.5%至8%。 她购买了
long bonds and she had that portfolio
长期债券，并持有该投资组合长达
for 55 years.
55年。
Wow.
哇。
Um she never spent any of the principal,
嗯，她从未动用过本金，
only the dividends and the interest. She
只用了股息和利息。 你知道，她
put my brother and I through college,
供我和哥哥上大学，
you know, she took care of her family
在家人
and her sisters when they fell on hard
和姐妹们遭遇困境时，她照顾她们
times. But her rule is very simple. No
。 但她的规则非常简单。 投资组合
more than 5% in any one stock or bond of
中任何单一股票或债券的持仓比例不得超过5%
the portfolio. and no more than 20% in
。 任何一个行业的占比都不得超过20%
any one sector ever. Ever. So when a
。 曾经。 所以当
stock ran up past five, she'd sell it
股票价格超过 5 美元时，她就会
down. This is not genius. This is just
低价卖出。 这算不上天才之举。 这只是
diversification.
分散投资而已。
when she passed and I I was the older
她去世的时候，我是
brother and I saw the portfolio cuz the
哥哥，我看到了她的资产组合，因为
lawyer said, "Listen, you got to come
律师说：“听着，你得过来一趟
down here. You're the executive of
。你是威尔的执行官
Will." And I said, "Yeah, but you know,
。” 我说：“是啊，但是你知道，
my mother was middle class."
我母亲是中产阶级。”
He said, "No, you got to come down
他说：“不，你得下来
here." um she kept her account secret
。” 嗯，她对
from both of her husbands. She wanted
自己的两个丈夫都隐瞒了自己的账户。 她想要拥有
her own independent money and back then
自己的独立资金，在当时这是
you could do that
可以做到的，
and um damn I mean what that portfolio
而且，我的天哪，我的意思是，那个投资组合的
did the performance was extraordinary.
表现简直非凡。
It was beyond any hedge fund guy or
这超出了任何对冲基金经理或
anything 55 years.
任何55岁人士的能力范围。
When I saw the results I said that's it.
看到结果后，我就说，就这么定了。
That's how I'm going to invest for the
我这辈子都会这样投资
rest of my life. Exactly the way Geette
。 完全就是吉特的
did. No more than 5%
做法。 任何一只股票的持仓比例都不得超过5%
in any one stock ever. No ma no matter
。 无论是
what it is and no more than 20% in any
什么，任何投资都不得超过20%，但
estate which is a very large part of
房地产除外，房地产占
what I have in net worth and I it's a
我净资产的很大一部分，占
it's a third. So that's broken the rule
三分之一。 所以这违反了规则，
but there's reasons for that and I'm
但这样做是有原因的，我
very happy with that portfolio. But um
对这个投资组合非常满意。 但是，
that if she if if everybody that's
如果所有
listening to this does that they will
听到这段话的人都这样做，他们就能
maintain and grow their wealth. But it's
保住并增加自己的财富。 但这是
people bet. They make big bets. They
人们的赌注。 他们敢于下大注。 他们就是
just they think they're so damn right.
觉得自己完全正确。
They put half their net worth into one
他们把一半的净资产投入到一个
sector or one stock and they get wiped
行业或一只股票，结果血本无归
out. That's what happens.
。 这就是事情的经过。
So would your mother pick the stocks
那么，你母亲会自己挑选股票，
herself or would she invest in an index
还是会投资指数
fund or
基金，或者进行
she indexed?
指数化投资？
She used Okay. So you can even back then
她用了“好的”。 所以，即使在那个时候，
you know they didn't have ETFs but they
你知道他们还没有ETF，但他们
had mutual funds that said their own the
有共同基金，这些基金声称自己只持有某
only stock in this mutual fund is it
只股票，而且这只股票
doesn't have any debt and it pays
没有任何债务，还会支付
dividends you know whatever they were
股息。你知道，
very rudimentary back then they were
那时候的基金非常原始，它们
just collections of stocks I think she
只是股票的集合。我想她的投资组合里大概
had like
有
28 names or something like that in the
28只股票，或者差不多是这个数量。
portfolio but if you looked at them they
但如果你仔细看，你会发现它们都是些非常
were really boring large cap names but
乏味的大盘股，不过
they were sectorally diverse there
它们在行业上是多元化的。
wasn't 10 sectors back then there was
那时候没有10个行业
only there there There wasn't 11, there
，只有
was 10. So, they didn't have real estate
10个。所以，当时他们没有把房地产
as a sector. So, but you know, I looked
作为一个行业板块。 所以，你知道，我看了之后
at it saying, "Wow, at least they're
心想，“哇，至少它们
really boring."
真的很无聊。”
You learned a lot about money from your
你从小就对金钱有了很多了解
early upbringing, right? From your that
，对吧？ 从你
early context.
早期的背景来看。   是的
Yeah. Because what she said to me was,
。 因为她对我说：
"Look,
“你看，
you know, I I even do this today with
你知道，即使现在，
wealthy people call me up all the time
有钱人也经常打电话给我
and say, "Look, um,
说，‘你看，嗯，
you know, they get divorced. this really
你知道，他们离婚了。’” 这真的是
this a very wealthy woman got divorced
一位非常富有的女士
recently and she said look I you know
最近离婚了，她说：“你知道，我正在
divorcing and she was a billionaire she
离婚，她是一位亿万富翁，她
was divorcing she was more
离婚时身价超过
multi-billionaire and so she said look I
亿万，所以她说：‘你看，
I'm getting everybody's calling me up um
每个人都打电话给我，想让我做
to be my advisor because I'm separating
我的顾问，因为我要
from my husband it's all his guys that
和我的丈夫分居了，
did all the management of our family
我们家族财富的所有管理都是他的人做的。
wealth would you be my adviser I said no
你愿意做我的顾问吗？’我说：‘不，
I don't do that um but you know I can I
我不做这个，但是我
can just give you some basic advice and
可以给你一些基本的建议，然后
you and hire people that stick on the
你可以雇佣那些能严格按照你的
mandate. And I gave her Georgette
指示行事的人。’” 我给了她乔治特的
strategy, but she I I had her do
策略，但我还让她做了其他一些事情
something else, too. I said, "Let's get
。 我说：“咱们拿
a piece of paper. You're a billionaire.
张纸来。你是个亿万富翁。把
paper on the last 90 days that you've
过去90天你花在
spent on whatever the hell it is. I
任何东西上的钱都写在这张纸上。我
don't care. And let's put on no
不在乎是什么。别用
computer, no spreadsheet on this. Let's
电脑，也别用电子表格。咱们
look at all the income that you've made
看看你现在的投资组合的所有收入
off your portfolio as it stands now,
，
whether it's gold you have or land or
不管是黄金、土地、
stocks or bonds.
股票还是债券。
Let's just do a a gut check on do you
咱们凭直觉看看你是不是
outspend yourself.
入不敷出。
She said, "Why would I give a shit?" I
” 她说：“我为什么要关心这个？” 我
said, "Wouldn't you like to know how
说：“难道你不想知道
much money you're burning living your
你现在这种生活方式光利息就要花掉多少钱吗
of interest? Maybe you have enough for
？” 也许你拥有的钱足够
the rest of your life, but maybe you
你过余生，但也许有一天你
want to give some of it to your family
想把其中的一部分留给家人，
one day or give it to charity. Wouldn't
或者捐给慈善机构。
you like to know?" Because one of my
你不想知道吗？因为我的
rules is never outspend yourself on any
原则之一就是，在任何
30 or 60 day cycle ever.
30天或60天的周期内，都绝不能超支。
Just ever. I don't have any debt. So, so
绝对不行。我没有任何债务。所以，
I'm very careful about that. And we went
我在这方面非常谨慎。我们之前遇到过
through this little thing.
这么点小事。
She freaked out. She was pissing away
她当时吓坏了。她简直是在挥霍
money. Just bleeding
金钱。
hundreds of thousands of dollars a week.
每周都要白白损失几十万美元。
I mean, I don't care how rich you are,
我的意思是，不管你多有钱，
you don't want to be stupid. And I said,
你都不想做傻事。我说：
"Does that shock you? One of two things
“这让你感到震惊吗？” 两件事必定会
has to happen. I mean, you're you're
发生其中一件。 我的意思是，你们
losing millions of dollars a quarter.
每个季度都在亏损数百万美元。
why? Why? Like you don't you you've had
为什么？ 为什么？ 就像你一样，没有
nobody restrict what you do with your
人限制你如何支配你的
money because you're going to have to
钱，因为你迟早要
sell stocks at some point or sell gold
卖掉股票、黄金
or sell land to keep this up and are you
或土地来维持这种局面，你
really that happy? Like what do you
真的那么开心吗？
what's all this [__] you're buying? Like
你买的这些东西到底是什么？
what is all this crap that you don't
你到底
need? It was a eye openener for her. So
需要哪些乱七八糟的东西？ 这件事让她大开眼界。 我的
I'm my point is most people don't do
意思是，大多数人都不做
that exercise. I don't care if you're
那种锻炼。 我不在乎你
only making 56,000 a year or 68 the
年收入是 56,000 美元还是 68,000 美元（
average salary.
平均工资）。
So, are you in the camp that you
所以，你是否也认为
shouldn't spend money on the small
不应该把钱花在
things like the coffee? If you don't
咖啡之类的小东西上？ 如果
need it, you should make the coffee at
不需要，你应该在家自己煮咖啡
home. Is that kind of
。 就是那种情况。我实在
I I just I can't stand it when I see
无法忍受看到
kids that are making 70 grand a year
年收入 7 万美元的孩子只花
spending $28 for lunch. I mean, that's
28 美元吃午饭。 我的意思是，这简直太
just stupid. It's just think about that
愚蠢了。 想想看，如果把这笔钱
in the context of that being put into an
纳入
index and making 8 to 8 to 10% a year
指数，在未来 50 年里每年获得 8% 到 10% 的收益，会是什么感觉？
What's an index for someone that doesn't
对于一个不了解的人来说，索引是什么？
So, okay. I mean, you know, I even have
好吧。 我的意思是，你知道，我甚至也有
it. I even built an app for this purpose
。 我甚至为此专门开发了一个应用程序，
just so I could There's many apps out
这样我就可以……市面上有很多类似的应用程序
there. You don't have to use mine.
。 你不必使用我的。
Mine's called Bean Stocks, but you just
我的账户叫做“豆类股票”，你只需要拿出
allocate 15% of your salary and it
工资的 15% 进行投资，它就会
automatically puts it into two buckets.
自动将这笔钱分成两份。
Some stocks and some bonds. The stocks
一些股票和一些债券。 这些股票
are ETFs, exchange traded funds that
是ETF，即交易所交易基金，它们
just track the S&amp;P 500. Very simply,
只追踪标普500指数。简单来说，
mine's a little
我的投资组合有点……
The S&amp;P 500 is the top 500 stocks.
标普500指数是市值排名前500的股票。   是的
Yeah. So, it's just, you know, people
。 所以，你知道，人们会
tell me, "Oh, I can beat the S&amp;P. I can
告诉我，“哦，我可以跑赢标普500指数。我可以
pick stocks." They're so full of crap.
选股。” 他们满嘴胡言。
not over the long period they can. So,
无法在他们能够的最长时间内完成。 所以，
it's better you might as well just own
你还不如直接持有
ETFs. I have a version of the S&amp;P that I
ETF。 我与其他人一起设计了一个标准普尔指数的版本，
out all the crappy balance sheets. But
剔除了所有糟糕的资产负债表。 但这只是
that's just me. You can just buy the
我个人的看法。 你可以直接购买
index that you want. You know, the ETF
你想要的指数。 你知道，ETF，
and then you pay low fees and then over
你支付的费用很低，随着
time it appreciates and then if you buy
时间的推移它会升值，然后如果你购买
some treasury bills or what fixed income
一些国库券或其他固定收益产品，那么
those when you're young and more of them
你年轻的时候应该少买一些，
when you're older. That's just
年老的时候应该多买一些。 那只是
diversification. But you you know the
分散投资而已。 但你知道，
best test I do with my kids' friends
我还会用我孩子的朋友们来做最好的测试
too. Go into a closet. Go into your
。 走进壁橱。 打开你的
closet and look at how much [__] you
衣橱，看看你有多少衣服从来
have you don't wear because you either
不穿，要么是因为你
bought it because you thought you were
买的时候以为自己会
going to wear it and never wore it or
穿，结果却
wore it once and you end up wearing 20%
一次也没穿过；要么是因为你只穿过一次，结果你总是穿的衣服只占
of your portfolio all of the time and
你所有衣服的 20%，剩下的
80% you you pissed away. I mean that's
80% 都被你浪费掉了。 我的意思是，这真是太
really stupid. And so for a young
愚蠢了。 所以，
person, a young woman or man, don't do
年轻人，无论是年轻女性还是年轻男性，都不要这样做
that. Start putting and just buy the
。 开始投资，只买
minimum stuff. And another thing I
最基本的东西。 还有一件事我
learned from my mother, this is
从母亲那里学到了，这很
interesting because I saw it happen at
有意思，因为我亲眼目睹了这件事在
her death. She,
她去世时发生。
you know, would buy two Chanel jackets a
你知道，她每年会买两件香奈儿外套
year, really expensive Chanel jackets,
，非常昂贵的香奈儿外套，
handmade Chanel jackets. I do business
手工制作的香奈儿外套。 我
with Chanel because of, you know, the
与香奈儿合作是因为，你知道，这是
legacy of my mother and the whole Coco
我母亲的遗志，还有可可·
Chanel thing and watches. I love those
香奈儿的品牌和腕表。 我喜欢他们
guys. And
。
her theory was this will never get old.
她的理论是，这种题材永远不会过时。
And it never did. A classic vintage
但事实并非如此。 一件保存完好的
Chanel jacket from the 50s that's
20世纪50年代经典香奈儿复古外套，
is worth a fortune today. The classic,
如今价值连城。 经典款，至今
it still wears beautifully. They're so
依然好看。 它们
well made. So, she wouldn't buy crap.
做工真好。 所以，她不会买垃圾。
She'd buy really good stuff, but a
她会买非常好的东西，但每次只买
little just small amounts of it. And
少量。
over the years, she'd built up this
多年来，她积累了一系列令人
portfolio of amazing clothing. And when
惊艳的服装作品。
she died, the women in in our family had
她去世后，我们家的女人们为了
a cat fight over her portfolio.
争夺她的投资组合而大打出手。
Unbelievable.
难以置信。
Is that in part why you have so many
这是否也是你拥有这么多
watches? I've noticed you have a watch
手表的原因之一？ 我注意到你
on either wrist right now.
现在两只手腕上都戴着手表。
Yeah, I'm pretty big in watches. I mean,
是的，我非常喜欢手表。 我的意思是，
but but watches to me, every piece I
但对我来说，手表，我
have marks something in my life that was
拥有的每一块手表都代表着我生命中一些
important. A deal, a child, graduation,
重要的事情。 一笔交易、一个孩子、毕业典礼，
um, you know, something. Every piece.
嗯，你知道，就是一些事。 每一件。
I've got a lot of watches.
我有很多手表。
How many have you got?
你有多少？
I I don't even say anymore because of
因为我买了
the insurance policy I have. I got a
保险，所以我现在都不敢再说了。 我得到了
lot.
很多。
Do you invest in You're talking about
你谈到
your your mother's investing strategy,
你母亲的投资策略时，
and one of the things you said is she
提到她
invested in dividend stocks.
投资了分红股票。   是的
Yes. What is a dividend stock and should
。 什么是分红股票？
I be investing in dividend stocks?
我应该投资分红股票吗？
Yeah, I mean, you know, a company if
是的，我的意思是，你知道，如果一家公司
it's profitable and it's operating, it
盈利且运营良好，其
business plan is working and it's
商业计划行之有效，并且
growing market share at some point says,
市场份额不断增长，那么在某个时候，它就会说：
"I'm going to distribute some of the
“我要把
success of our profits to our
我们部分利润分配给我们的
shareholders." That's a dividend. And so
股东。” 那是分红。 所以
they send that cash to you and you can
他们会把这笔钱寄给你，你可以
either redeploy it in other ways or live
把它用于其他用途，或者
off it or whatever. Many tech stocks
靠它生活，或者做任何你想做的事情。 直到最近，许多科技股
until recently did not pay dividends.
都不派发股息。
But now the behemoth tech stocks do pay
但现在，科技巨头们确实会派发
dividends because the demand of an aging
股息，因为人口老龄化带来的需求
population is I need to eat and so I
是：我需要吃饭，所以我
like to own the stock for growth but I
喜欢持有股票以求增长，但我
also want to get some of the profits and
也想获得一些利润，
so dividend paying stocks uh used to be
所以派息股票……过去是
utilities uh but not so today. Every
公用事业股，但现在不是了。
every sector has dividend paying stocks.
每个行业都有派发股息的股票。
So I prefer to own dividend paying
所以我更倾向于持有派息
stocks div payers and then I also own
股票，同时也持有
fixed income products. I also own crypto
固定收益产品。 我现在也持有加密货币，还
now and I own alternative assets like
持有
gold and watches. My watch collection's
黄金和手表等其他资产。 尽管市场有所回调，但我的手表收藏
actually done quite well even though
实际上表现相当不错
there's been a correction. There's
。 虽然市场
volatility, but I have some watches that
波动较大，但我有一些手表
have, you know, I bought for
，你知道，我当时花了
200,000 that are worth over a million
20 万美元买的，现在价值超过 100 万美元
today.
。
Crypto. So, are you still bullish on
加密货币。 那么，你仍然看好
crypto as an investment?
加密货币作为投资吗？
Yeah, I am actually, but people get
是的，我确实是，但人们常常把
crypto confused with its real potential.
加密货币与其真正的潜力混淆起来。
Um,
嗯，
uh, let's talk about digital payment
呃，我们来谈谈数字支付
systems because what's about to pass
系统吧，因为即将通过的
first, we're days away from this
第一项法案，也
happening, is the Genius Act, which is
就是《天才法案》（Genius Act，
actually the Stablecoin Act. It was just
实际上是《稳定币法案》），再过几天就会生效了。
passed by the Senate 48 hours ago. It's
参议院48小时前刚刚通过了这项法案。 它要
going back to the House. I I actually
退回众议院了。 实际上，我
worked on that bill two years ago. So,
两年前就参与过那项法案的制定工作。 所以，
if that bill passes, it's really nothing
如果这项法案获得通过，那也
to do with speculating on crypto. It's a
与投机加密货币无关。 这是一种
new form of payment. So, if I wanted to
新型的支付方式。 所以，如果我想
order a watch in uh from Simone Brit,
从 Simone Brit 那里订购一块手表，
who's somebody I buy watches from. He's
我经常从她那里买手表。 他是
a master watch maker. Right now, I have
一位技艺精湛的制表师。 现在我
to take US dollars, I've got to get
必须接受美元，我必须先
through a know your client um
通过了解客户的
prerogative. Um I'm treated like a
权利程序。 呃，我
criminal by transferring $100,000 over.
转账10万美元就被当成罪犯对待了。
Turn it into Swiss Franks. Takes about a
兑换成瑞士法郎。 大约需要一周时间
week. I get screwed for about 200 basis
。 我在这整个过程中损失了大约 200 个
points in the whole thing. If I if he
基点。 如果他
accepted USDC, which is actually a
接受了 USDC（实际上是一种
stable coin back with the US dollar,
与美元挂钩的稳定币），并且
just went public, very successful IPO. I
刚刚上市，IPO 非常成功。 我
was a shareholder in that company, too.
也是那家公司的股东之一。
That's one of my best IPOs in the last
这是我近两年来最成功的IPO之一
two years. The transaction would happen
。 交易将
in less than a second and the fees would
在不到一秒的时间内完成，费用仅为
be at hundth of what the costs are right
目前成本的百分之一
now. So it's a digital payment system.
。 所以它是一个数字支付系统。
The price doesn't it's not it's no
价格并非
speculation on it's backed by the US
投机所得，而是由
dollar treasury bills. So it's sort of a
美元国债支撑。 所以这是一种
new form of of digital payment. That's
新型的数字支付方式。 这
different than Bitcoin which is a
与比特币不同，比特币是一种
speculation. It's if you believe in
投机行为。 如果你相信
Bitcoin, you think it's a digital gold
比特币，认为它是数字黄金，
and you live through the volatility. I
并且愿意承受它的波动，那就行了。 我
believe in both. I believe that that
两者都相信。 我认为，
crypto will be the 12th sector of the
加密货币在一段时间内将成为标普500指数的第12个板块，
S&amp;P in some period of time because it
因为它为
provides productivity to all 11 other
其他11个板块都带来了生产力
sectors. So the way I own it is I own
。 所以我拥有这些资产的方式就是我拥有
the exchanges. My exchange in one called
交易所。 我
Wonderfy up in Canada just got acquired
在加拿大一家名为 Wonderfy 的交易所，就在一
last week or two weeks ago by Robin
两周前被 Robinhood 收购了
Hood. I'm happy because I think Vlad who
。 我很高兴，因为我觉得
runs Robin Hood's great and now he's got
经营 Robinhood 的 Vlad 非常出色，现在他
a million plus accounts in Canada and
在加拿大拥有超过一百万个账户，而且
market that he never participated in.
他之前从未涉足过这个市场。
But the point is this is never going
但关键是，这种情况永远不会
away. It's going to stay forever. So how
消失。 它将永远留在这里。 那么，如何
do you participate? You can buy some
参与呢？ 你可以像
Bitcoin just like you can buy gold, buy
购买黄金一样购买比特币，可以
it in an ETF or actually own it
通过ETF购买，也可以直接拥有比特币
yourself. You can buy the exchanges. You
。 你可以购买交易所。
can use um you know you can buy Circle
你知道，现在你可以购买Circle的
stock now it's public. You can Circle
股票了，它已经上市了。 您可以使用 Circle
makes USDC. you can buy USDC in in an
生成 USDC。 您现在可以在账户中购买 USDC，
account and make 4.1% interest on it
并获得 4.1% 的利息
right now. So, there's a lot of ways to
。 所以，有很多
participate, but yes, I'm here to stay,
参与的方式，是的，我会一直在这里，
but I've g I've grown up. I was around
但我已经长大了。 我亲身经历了
during the period where the crypto
加密货币
cowboys lived and and I survived that
投机者的时代，我活了下来，
all and I even testified in front of the
甚至在
Senate and the House and whatever else
参议院、众议院以及其他各种
the testimonies were during the the
场合作证，度过了那段
tumultuous period and most of those guys
动荡时期，而那些人中的大多数都
went to jail.
进了监狱。   就
Your portfolio in terms of Bitcoin
比特币
allocation or crypto allocation, what is
或加密货币配置而言，您
it now?
目前的投资组合构成如何？   差不多已经全部投入了
It's at about allin. Uh we we marked to
。
market last month it was 19.1%.
上个月我们按市值计价，结果是 19.1%。
19.1%.
19.1%。   是的
Yeah. We have to keep it under 20. It's
。 我们必须把它控制在20以下。这是
a sector. So but remember in that is the
一个行业。 但请记住，这其中包含了
cryptos itself, Bitcoin, the USDC and
加密货币本身，比特币、USDC 以及
companies like Circle and everything
Circle 等基础设施公司的股票
else. I've got you know it was a very
等等。 我知道这是一次非常
successful IPO. One of the first things
成功的IPO。
most people do when they get a bit of
大多数人拿到一些
money, usually from their their job, is
钱（通常是工作所得）后做的第一件事就是
they get a mortgage on a house because
申请房屋抵押贷款，因为
we're kind of taught as we grow up that
我们从小就被灌输这样一种观念：
the best way to make or the the not
创造财富的最佳途径，或者说，
maybe the best, but the most obvious way
或许不是最佳途径，但最显而易见的途径
to create wealth is to buy your first
就是购买第一套
home.
房产。
Yeah, there's a very basic rule for that
是的，这方面有一个非常基本的规则，
and I understand it and I did the same
我理解，我也做了同样的
thing. But what I made sure again from
事情。 但我再次叮嘱
my mother was never let the mortgage and
母亲，房贷和
the cost of maintaining the house be
房屋维护费用绝不能
more than onethird
超过
of your income. Onethird of your income.
你收入的三分之一。 你收入的三分之一。
If it's more than onethird, you bought
如果超过三分之一，说明你买的
too much house. So it's better to buy a
房子太大了。 所以，最好先买一套面积
house that's maybe it's only going to be
可能只有
1,900 square feet to start in a
1900 平方英尺的房子，即使
neighborhood that you may not want to
你最终可能不会在这个社区
stay for the rest of your life, but
住一辈子，但从这个角度来看，这样可以
start to acrue the benefit of real
开始积累房地产带来的好处
estate from that point of view. Learn
。 学习
how to manage it. Maybe you rent part of
如何管理它。 或许你可以把一部分出租
it out or whatever, but it can't be more
出去，但出租所得不能超过
than a third of your income. The mistake
你收入的三分之一。
that people made, and they're starting
人们犯的错误，现在他们开始
to suffer from it now, is when money was
为此付出代价，就是当资金
so cheap, mortgage mortgage rates were
非常便宜，抵押贷款利率
under 4%, they were 3.2% some of them,
低于 4%（有些甚至低至 3.2%）时，
they bought massive houses. And now
他们购买了巨大的房产。 现在
they're running into having to refinance
他们不得不以
those houses at much higher rates, more
更高的利率（超过
than 7%. And it's becoming 60, 70, 80%
7%）为这些房屋进行再融资。 而且它正逐渐占到他们收入的 60%、70%、80%
of their income. They're screwed. They
。 他们完蛋了。 他们
bought too much house. So, it's about
买的房子太大了。 所以，关键在于
making sure that you can manage that.
确保你能做到这一点。
And also you want some diversification.
而且你也想分散投资。
Yes, a mortgage is okay, particular if
是的，抵押贷款是可以接受的，特别是如果
you're having a family because you're
你有家庭的话，因为你
going to pay rent or you're gonna pay a
要么付房租，要么付
mortgage, one of the two. But you want
抵押贷款，二者必居其一。 但是，
some diversification in starting to
在开始
build up that investment account for
积累退休投资账户
when you retire so that you have
时，你需要进行一些多元化投资，这样退休后才能有
something to live off. If you only put
生活保障。 如果
aside 15% if you're you're making 70,000
你年收入7万美元，从
you're 25, you'll have over a million
25岁开始每年拿出15%的收入进行投资，并且全部投资于标普500指数，那么到现在你就能拥有超过150万
and a half dollars if you just invested
美元。
That's what that's what history has told
历史就是这么告诉
you.
我们的。
In what time frame?
在什么时间范围内？
Your whole career. I mean, you're going
你的整个职业生涯。 我的意思是，你会从
to be 65, you're 25, 65. You just stick
65岁变成25岁，再变成65岁。你只要坚持
with that protocol and you'll watch it
这个方案，就会看到它不断
grow. You'll watch it grow. You go up
成长。 你会看着它成长。
and down as the market goes up and down.
随着市场涨跌，你的收入也会随之波动。
Some years it'll go flat, whatever. But
有些年份它会停滞不前，无所谓。 但有些
it's the people that don't even think
人根本不考虑
ahead and find themselves at 45 mired in
长远，到了 45 岁就发现自己深陷
debt, including a mortgage. You want to
债务泥潭，其中包括房贷。 你想
get rid of your mortgage in your 40s.
在40多岁的时候还清房贷。
Most people's primary investment asset
大多数人的主要投资资产
is the house they buy.
是他们购买的房屋。
Is that
是的
Yes, it is. But it's also the debt they
，没错。 但他们也
own. It's a primary asset. How much debt
背负着债务。 这是一项主要资产。
does it have on it? It's only the equity
它有多少债务？ 只有股权
value is the asset. So, if you're buying
价值才是资产。 所以，如果你买了
a house that's too big and it's you've
一套太大的房子，
only put down 10% and it's 90% mortgage,
首付只有 10%，剩下的 90% 是抵押贷款，那么
what do you really own? you really own
你到底拥有多少呢？
at whatever price it is. Sometimes
无论价格如何，这10%的股份都归你所有。 有时
housing goes flat for a while. It's it's
房地产市场会经历一段低迷期。 房子大了就没
okay, but it's not okay if it's too much
问题，但如果房子太大就不行了
house.
。
If you're a 25year-old and you're on
如果你今年 25 岁，年收入达到你之前提到的
that 70k that you talked about, and your
7 万美元，你的
objective was to make money, you don't
目标是赚钱，你
have kids, you don't you're not in a
没有孩子，也没有
relationship,
伴侣，
would you buy a house?
你会买房吗？
No. No, I wouldn't because why do I need
不，我不会，因为
a house if I'm only unless I'm renting
如果我只是自住，除非是出租
as an income property? I'm buying a
作为投资房产，否则我为什么要买房呢？ 我买房是
house because I'm getting married. I'm
因为我要结婚了。 我要
going to raise a family. I need a house.
组建家庭。 我需要一套房子。
I mean,
我的意思是，这就是
is that the the use case for buying a
买房的用途吗
house? You think?
？ 您认为？
I think it is. People, but it's not.
我认为是的。 人们，但事实并非如此。
There are many people that say, "I love
很多人都说：“我喜欢
real estate. I'm going to buy three
房地产。我要买三套
houses. I'm going to rent them out."
房子，然后出租。”
That's a different business. And I know
那是另一回事。 我知道有些
people in their 20s that do that. In
二十多岁的年轻人也这样做。
fact, they're successful. That's all
事实上，他们很成功。
they do. And so, that their job is to
他们只会做这些。 因此，他们的工作就是
find houses, buy them, fix them up, and
寻找房屋、购买房屋、进行修缮并
rent them. And they manage that
出租。 他们成功管理了这一
geographically tight portfolio. It
地域分布较为集中的投资组合。 这种情况
happens a lot in student housing. for
在学生宿舍里经常发生。
example, got a good friend who's
例如，我有个好朋友从事
involved in student housing. He's very
学生公寓相关工作。 他非常
successful. He just focuses on one
成功。 他只专注于一个
aspect, buildings that rent to students
方面，那就是把楼房租给学生，
and he manages it and he, you know,
他负责管理这些楼房，同时，你知道，他还要
raises a family. He's successful, but
养家糊口。 他很成功，但这只是
that's one thing he does. That's not the
他擅长的一件事。 这和
same as saying, "I'm going to buy a
说“我要买
house cuz I'm I just got married and I'm
房子，因为我刚结婚，而且我打算在
in the next 24 months." Then you should
未来24个月内生孩子”是不一样的。 那你应该
have a house. But if you're you said to
有房子了。 但如果你对
me, "I'm single. I want to make money."
我说：“我是单身，我想赚钱。”
I wouldn't buy a house. That's not the
我不会买房子。 那不是
number one asset class. I think I'd get
排名第一的资产类别。 我想我会建立
a diversified portfolio and just ride
一个多元化的投资组合，先靠它过
the pony with that for a while until I
一段时间，直到
meet that special person I'm going to,
遇到那个要和我一起
you know, raise a family with and then I
组建家庭的特别的人，然后我就
have a little nest egg I can work with.
可以攒下一笔积蓄了。
I mean,
我的意思是，
wealth creation
创造财富归根结底可以用
comes down to one word, discipline.
一个词来概括：自律。   就是这样。
That's it. The ability to look at
能够审视
something and say, "I'm not going to buy
某样东西，然后说：“我不会买
that. I'm going to keep that money
它。我要让这笔钱
working for me." Not many people have
为我工作。” 很少有人具备
that discipline.
这种自律性。
Wealthy people have that discipline. You
富人都具备这种自律精神。 当你
meet them later in life, you realize
长大后遇到他们时，你会意识到，
when they were young and had nothing,
当他们年轻一无所有时，
even the ones that were employees their
即使是那些
whole lives that are now financially
一辈子都在打工、现在经济
free had the discipline to say no.
自由的人，也都有拒绝的自律精神。
There's so much stuff you don't need.
有很多东西你其实并不需要。
And you should never buy a watch unless
除非你买得起，否则千万不要买手表
you can afford it. Ever go on debt for a
。 你有没有
watch because people hear this stuff
因为听到这种说法而负债买手表，比如
say, "I'm going to buy watches like with
“我要买那种
red bands." No, you're not. That's why I
红表带的手表”。 不，你不是。 这就是为什么我
wear watches now that cost under $500 to
现在戴价格低于 500 美元的手表，以此向
show kids you want to get into herology.
孩子们表明你想进入英雄学领域。
You don't have to spend, you know,
你不需要花
$50,000. Here's a here's a Timex for
5万美元。 这里有一块 Timex 手表，售价
$265. It looks beautiful. Get that.
265 美元。 它看起来很漂亮。 明白了。
You said, uh, you know, don't buy the
你说过，呃，你知道，在
house until you meet your partner, etc.
遇到伴侣之前不要买房子等等。
success in your view?
在你看来，你爱上的那个人会对你的财务状况、你的金钱、你的成功机会产生多大的影响？
It's everything. Are you kidding? I
它包含了一切。 你在开玩笑吧？ 我的
mean, it's it's everything. If you read
意思是，它就是一切。 如果你读了，
I mean, think about this.
我的意思是，想想这件事。
You you need to find somebody if you're
如果你是创业者，你需要找到合适的人
an entrepreneur. So that's for the we're
。 所以，
talking about the third now that want to
现在我们来谈谈第三位想要
go on the rocket ship ride. You better
乘坐火箭飞船的人。 你最好
find somebody that's willing to tolerate
找个能容忍
the fact that you're never home for the
你头十年都不在家的人
first 10 years. They're going to raise a
。 他们打算
family by themselves because there's no
独自组建家庭，因为
balance in life. That that idea of
生活没有平衡。 那种平衡的概念
balance is complete [__] I mean,
完全是胡扯。 我的意思是，
it's just [__] You have to work so
这简直是胡说八道。
hard to compete globally these days in
如今，在
every sector. you're going to work your
各个领域，要想在全球范围内竞争，都必须付出巨大的努力。 你会
ass off and it's not going to happen
拼命努力，而且这不会轻易发生。
over I mean Anna Sky did it in three
我的意思是，安娜·斯凯用了三年时间就做到了，
years but she had worked much harder
但她
previously it was not her first deal but
之前付出了更多努力。这并非她的第一笔交易，但
she was just lucky I mean she
她只是运气好。我的意思是，她有
was this the cat DNA
猫的基因，
cat thing I mean she's she she but she's
我的意思是，她，
you know she's she's working again she's
你知道，她又开始工作了，她
back she wants to work I mean that's
回来了，她想工作。我的意思是，这就是
what happens you never stop working but
现实，你永远不会停止工作。但
the thing is
关键在于
that partnership
合伙关系，
and this is what people don't get about
而这正是人们对
marriage
婚姻的误解所在。
marriage Marriage is a business. I know
婚姻是一门生意。 我知道
people go nuts when I say that, but it's
我这么说会让很多人抓狂，但这毕竟是
a business. And the first child you're
生意。 你即将拥有的第一个孩子就是
going to have is money. It's going to be
金钱。 这将是你的
the first child, and it's going to sit
第一个孩子，他/她
at the table with you every day. It's
每天都会和你一起坐在餐桌旁。 它就
it's there sitting there. If you don't
放在那里。
have money, you don't have a marriage. I
没有钱，就没有婚姻。 我的
mean, the reason people get married is
意思是，人们结婚的原因是
to form a form of financial stability so
为了建立某种形式的经济稳定，
that they can afford a family. And you
以便能够养家糊口。 你
have to figure out,
要明白，
you know, I'm I'm I've been with my wife
我和我妻子在一起
a long time and we've been separated for
很久了，我们已经分居
a couple of years, but you know, family
几年了，但是你知道，家庭
is very important to me. So, I we got
对我来说非常重要。 所以，我们又
back together again. We you know, our
复合了。 你知道吗，是我们的
daughter got us back together. I'm very
女儿让我们重归于好。 我很
happy we did it. But it's
高兴我们做到了。 但
we make financial decisions together. We
财务决策都是我们共同做出的。 我们
we always check in, you know, anything
总是会去确认，你知道，任何
that's material,
实质性的事情，
you know, if we're going to do a
比如我们要进行
renovation or something. And and I
翻新之类的。 我为此
respect her for that. I have a lot of
尊重她。 我非常
respect for her because she doesn't just
尊重她，因为她不只是
spend money. We didn't have any money
花钱。 我们
when we started. We had nothing. And so
创业之初身无分文。 我们一无所有。 所以，
that's why a great marriage can work
美好的婚姻之所以能够长久，是
because you build it together. You
因为你们共同经营。 你
really care about it. You care about
真的很在意这件事。 你很关心
your family. You also care about what
你的家人。 你也很在意
you you've created in wealth. And I
自己创造的财富。 我
consider my money her money. You like
觉得我的钱就是她的钱。 你喜欢她，
because she was the family that let me
因为她的家人让我
go and do this stuff. Now I don't have
去做这些事。 现在我
the same relationship with our kids that
和孩子们的关系不像
she does because she raised them. But
她那样，因为他们是她养大的。 但这
that's the thing you give up and you
就是你必须放弃的东西，你
have to give something up. That's it.
必须放弃一些东西。 就是这样。
You can be a great father, a great
你可以成为一位伟大的父亲，一位出色的
provider, but you're never going to have
养家糊口的人，但你永远无法拥有
the closest that she had reading them
她
stories when they were young. I wasn't
小时候给孩子们讲故事时那种亲密无间的感觉。 我当时不
there. But, you know, the outcome has
在场。 但是，你知道，结果还
been good. I think everybody looks at
不错。 我想每个人看到
that and says, "All right, that's
这个都会说：“好吧，这
great."
太棒了。”
But my mother never believed in
但我母亲从不相信人有
entitlement. And so, I don't believe in
特权。 所以，我也不相信
it either. I'm not gifting my kids a ton
。 我不会给孩子们一大笔钱
of money. You know, I I want them to
。 你知道，我希望他们能够
launch, and they've done that
成功启动，而他们也
successfully. They got to they got to
成功做到了。 他们开始
work. You know, they got to do their
工作了。 你知道，他们得做他们该做的
thing. I've heard you say before that
事。 我以前听你说过，
you'll ever make is who you'll marry.
你一生中最重要的财务决定就是和谁结婚。   是的
Yes.
。
Why?
为什么？
Because think of the geometric loss of
想想财富的几何级数损失吧
wealth. Every time you get divorced,
。 每次离婚，
you pay the woman that you divorced or
你都要支付给离婚的妻子或
man and you pay the government
丈夫
a third often through capital gains and
三分之一的赡养费，还要通过资本利得税和资产
liquidation because you can't separate
清算的方式向政府支付三分之一，因为有时如果
all the assets without liquidating them
不清算资产，就无法分割所有资产
sometimes. So, you've got the government
。 所以，政府就
sitting there. You've got the other
坐在那里。 你的
spouse sitting there. This is the
配偶就坐在那里。 这是
stupidest thing you can ever do. It took
你所能做的最愚蠢的事。
your whole life to
你花了毕生精力才
to actually create this nest egg.
攒下这笔积蓄。
Could be, you know, you're 45 or
有可能，你知道，你已经45岁了或者
whatever. You you've got a comfortable
其他什么年纪。 你原本过着舒适的
life and all of a sudden you don't like
生活，突然间你不喜欢
your wife or husband. Think about that
你的妻子或丈夫了。 好好想想吧，
for a while because you are going to
因为你将
wipe out up to twothirds of your wealth.
损失高达三分之二的财富。
You better really like somebody else a
你最好真的非常喜欢别人
lot. And frankly,
。 坦白说，
sometimes it's not the other person that
有时候
you're divorcing. It's you. You're the
你要离婚的并不是另一个人。 是你。
problem. If you're getting married for
问题出在你身上。 如果你
the third time, you're a guy or woman.
第三次结婚，那么你就是男的或女的。
It's not them. It's you. There's
不是他们。 是你。
something wrong with you. And you should
你肯定有问题。 而且你
probably not get into another economic
最好不要再加入其他经济
union. You should probably just date
联盟了。 你最好一直谈恋爱
till you drop dead because it's stupid.
直到死去，因为这很愚蠢。
Marriages are tough. I mean, they're
婚姻很艰难。 我的意思是，他们很
tough. Anybody who's been married for
强悍。 结婚
more than 20 years knows exactly what
超过20年的人都知道
I'm talking about. But they have they
我在说什么。 但他们所获得的
acrew more benefit than than you know
利益比你所能想象的要多得多
anything. So if as long if you're happy
。 所以，只要你
51% of the day with your wife, stay with
一天中有 51% 的时间和妻子相处融洽，就和
him or her husband or wife. You that's
他（丈夫或妻子）在一起吧。 你
very important. How often do you think
很重要。 你认为
divorces are a result of money issues?
离婚中有多少是由于金钱问题造成的？
Well, you may be shocked at this. I
你可能会对此感到震惊。 我
wrote a book um about this and I decided
写了一本书，嗯，就是关于这个的，我
uh men and women of money a long time
很久
ago, 10 years plus. Right there it is.
以前，大概10多年前，就决定写一本关于有钱男人和女人的书了。 就在那儿。
And I did some research and I I uh went
我做了一些调查，然后我去
to meet some of the top um divorce
拜访了北美一些顶尖的离婚
lawyers in North America, in New York,
律师，包括纽约、
in Boston, and other cities.
波士顿和其他城市的律师。
And I said, "Look, I I want to kind of
我说：“你看，我想做
do a pie chart of reasons for divorce
一个饼图，列出导致离婚的原因，
that seemed 50% seem to end divorce
其中 50% 的原因似乎会
within 5 to seven years."
在 5 到 7 年内结束离婚。”
Every one of them, they didn't know each
他们每个人都说，他们彼此并不认识
other, said, "It's not infidelity.
，却都说：“这不是出轨，跟出轨一点
Nothing to do with it. Most marriages
关系都没有。大多数婚姻
can u survive infidelity.
都能挺过出轨，但
they can't survive financial stress.
撑不住经济压力。
And so what happens invariably is you
所以，通常的情况是，你
fall in love, but you didn't do any due
坠入爱河，但你没有
diligence on that person's spending
对对方的消费
habits or their financial history
习惯或财务历史进行任何尽职调查，
because La More is so wonderful in the
因为爱情初期总是那么美好。
early days. You didn't do any diligence
你没有调查
on their family or them or their brother
过他们的家庭、他们本人、他们的兄弟姐妹，或者他们
or bankruptcy in the past or whatever it
过去的破产记录等等
is. And then you get married and you
。然后你们结婚了，你
know the euphoria starts to wear off and
知道，最初的激情开始消退，
you notice that the other is outspending
你发现对方花钱比
you
你多，
just buying a lot of stuff
买了很多超出
beyond your means.
你经济能力的东西。这就是
And that starts the first friction. And
第一次摩擦的开始。
then that credit card comes in with
然后，信用卡账单来了，欠了
$100,000 on it at 23% interest and
10万美元，年利率23%，又
purse was bought or whatever the hell it
买了个包包之类的东西
is.
。
and you're you're starting to sink
你开始陷入困境，
because you may have married somebody
因为你可能嫁给了一个
who can't stop spending. This is just a
无法停止消费的人。这只是一个
typical
典型的例子，有些
there are people that can't have no
人就是控制不住自己。”
discipline. They just can't. They got to
自律？他们就是做不到。他们非得
have the boat. They got to have this.
拥有那艘船，非得拥有这个，
They got to have that. And they pressure
非得拥有那个。他们还互相施压，让
their other to say, "Look, I want to
对方说：“听着，我也想跟
keep up with the Joneses next door, even
隔壁的琼斯一家比，即使
though they may only each have a salary
他们每个人年薪可能只有
of 100 grand each. Can't do it." And
十万美元。”  “做不到。”
they have kids and they're trying to put
他们有孩子，还要供
them through college.
他们上大学。
That's divorce. That's why almost 90% of
这就是离婚。几乎90%的
of unions break up is is is that classic
婚姻破裂都是因为这个原因，典型的
financial pressure and divorce gets them
经济压力，而离婚让他们
out of that mess because they can no
摆脱了困境，因为他们
longer spend on your credit card
再也不能用你的信用卡消费了
anymore. But it's a horrible way to go.
。但这是一种糟糕的方式。
So I, you know, I'm an investor in a
所以，你知道，我投资了一家
company called Hello Prenup that does
叫Hello Prenup的公司，这家公司为离婚人士提供婚前协议服务，也
divorces for does um uh prenups for
为
women and prenups forced during the
女性提供婚前协议服务，包括婚前协议，以及在
euphoric period diligence.
恋爱初期被迫签署的婚前协议。
It's that simple. You're going to find
就这么简单。你要
out if that person has a financial
弄清楚这个人婚前是否存在经济
problem going into the marriage. They
问题。他们
have to disclose
必须披露
their financial background.
自己的财务背景。
So, you talk about these five love
所以，你谈到金钱的五种爱的
languages of money. The mooch, someone
语言。“蹭吃蹭喝的”，就是那种
who won't pay for anything,
什么都不付的人，
right?
对吧？
Should I date someone like that?
我应该和这样的人约会吗？
It's a warning signal. It's a problem.
这是一个警告信号。这是一个问题。
It's a problem. So,
这是一个问题。
or they don't really want you for
或者，他们并不真的想要你的
companionship. They just want you for
陪伴。他们只是想要你的
financial support.
经济支持。“挥霍
The spender holic. Someone who always
无度的”，就是那种总是花钱如流水的人。
offers to pay for everything to appear
为了显得
popular and successful.
受欢迎和成功，什么都愿意付。
Bad morning sign. Huge. I mean that
糟糕的早晨征兆。非常严重。我的意思是，这
isn't that is insecurity measurable by
不仅仅是缺乏安全感，而是可以用
cash outlay.
金钱支出来衡量的。
The loafer. Someone who has no ambition
游手好闲的人。没有抱负，
and drive for money.
对金钱没有动力。
A void with extreme prejudice.
一个充满偏见的空虚之人。
The thief. Someone who steals.
小偷。偷东西的人。
You can have no tolerance for that.
你绝对不能容忍这种人。
And the meanie. A balanced spender who
还有吝啬鬼。一个量入为出的节俭者。我喜欢这种人。
Love that. Marry a meanie. That's it.
嫁给一个吝啬鬼。就是这样。就是这样。这样的
marriages that last an entire life.
婚姻才能持续一生。就是这样。
That's it. That's what you're looking
这就是你想要的
for. That's great advice right there.
。这真是个好建议。
Whatever the book costs, that's that's
无论这本书多少钱，这都是
the best value right there. And then ask
最划算的。然后问问
yourself, am I dating one of these or
自己，我约会的对象是这种人吗
not? You know, you know, you should talk
？你知道，你应该
about money on the third date. Think
在第三次约会时谈论金钱。想想
about a date. Think about dating. First
约会。想想约会。第一次
date, oh my goodness, this is a really
约会，哦，我的天哪，这个
interesting person. Um or not, then
人真有趣。嗯，或者不是，那就
there's never a second date. second
永远不会有第二次
date. I want to learn more. I'm really
约会。我想学习 更进一步。我真的很有
interested. You're going into a third
兴趣。你们要进行第三次约会了
date. There's something going on.
。肯定有什么事发生了。肯定有
There's something going on. You both
什么事发生了。你们
want to meet again. That's the first
都想再次见面。这时
time you should say, "Look, I know this
你应该第一次说：“我知道这很
is crazy, but we're here together a
疯狂，但我们
third time because something's going on
第三次见面是因为肯定有什么事发生了
here, and I'm just wondering what are
，我只是想知道
your long-term goals? I mean, it's not
你的长期目标是什么？” 我的意思是，这无
about our marriage or anything else
关乎我们的婚姻或其他任何事情，
other than we're having a great time,
我们只是过得很开心，
but what are your ambitions? I'm really
但你的抱负是什么？ 我对
interested in you. I'd like to know what
你很感兴趣。 我想知道
you think. And the maybe the woman says
你的想法。 也许女人会说，
or the guy says, "What are you checking
或者男人会说：“你在看
me out?" You say, "Yeah, yeah, I'm
我什么？” 你说：“是啊，是啊，我
really interested in you." It's a form
对你真的很有兴趣。” 这是一种
of finding out if the connection, you
了解彼此关系的方式，你
know, I I should be a marriage
知道，我应该去做婚姻
counselor. That's what I think. I mean,
咨询师。 我也是这么想的。 我的意思是，约会就像
dance, but it should involve exploring
跳舞，但它也应该包括探讨
where we're going financially.
我们在财务上的未来方向。
For many years, you've probably seen
多年来，你可能一直看到
this iPad sat in front of me. You've
这台 iPad 放在我面前。 你
probably wondered what's on it. and I'm
可能想知道上面有什么。 我
going to tell you today because they're
今天要告诉大家这件事，因为他们
now our show sponsor thankfully. It's an
现在是我们的节目赞助商，真是太好了。 这是一个
app called GoodNotes and it's where I
叫做 GoodNotes 的应用程序，我把
store all of my research, all of my
所有的研究资料、所有
information, but also where I take notes
信息都存储在这个应用程序里，而且
in real time when the guest is speaking
当客人和我说话时，我也会实时地在这个应用程序里做笔记
to me. I love this app because it's so
。 我喜欢这个应用，因为它功能
dynamic, but also because of this new
丰富，而且还有一个
feature which is called Ask Goodnotes.
叫做“Ask Goodnotes”的新功能。
It's basically my AI companion. I can
它基本上就是我的人工智能伙伴。 我有时只需几秒钟就能
search the 200 pages sometimes of notes
搜索到面前多达 200 页的笔记
and information that I have in front of
和资料
me in just seconds. I can type into the
。 我可以在
ask goodnotes feature, what was the name
Goodnotes 的提问功能中输入“
of Kevin's mother? I'm speaking to Kevin
凯文的母亲叫什么名字？” 我正在和凯文·
Olio on the podcast. He starts talking
奥利奥一起录制播客节目。 他开始谈论
about his mother. I have a couple of
他的母亲。 我只有几
seconds to figure out what she's called
秒钟的时间来弄清楚她叫什么名字，
so I can ask him a question about her in
这样我才能礼貌地问他一个关于她的问题
a polite way. Ask GoodNotes looks
。  Ask GoodNotes 会
through all of my notes, responds back
查看我的所有笔记，并
to me in seconds. If you're someone that
在几秒钟内回复我。 如果你像我一样
loves taking notes, but your notes are a
喜欢记笔记，但你的笔记却
mess and you can't read your own
一团糟，而且你根本看不懂自己的
handwriting, i.e. me, I think GoodNotes
字迹，那么我认为 GoodNotes
might be the solution for you. and ask
或许能解决你的问题。 不妨试试
GoodNotes, which is their new AI
GoodNotes，他们的新 AI
feature, might just be the tool that
功能或许就能
turns you into an organized person.
让你成为一个井井有条的人。   我的确有这种
That's certainly how it feels for me.
感觉。
So, I asked GoodNotes if they would give
于是，我问 GoodNotes 是否可以给
my listeners a 30-day free trial to try
我的听众提供 30 天的免费试用期
it out. And they've given us one on iOS
。 他们已经为 iOS
and Mac. So, if you want to use that
和 Mac 用户提供了相应的版本。 所以，如果您想使用这
30-day free trial, go to
30 天免费试用期，请访问
goodnotes.com/doac
goodnotes.com/doac
or sign up now for your yearly
或立即注册年度
subscription for just $9.99 per year.
订阅，每年只需 9.99 美元。
That's $9.99 per year. Go to
那就是每年9.99美元。 访问
goodnotes.com/doac.
goodnotes.com/doac。
I've built companies from scratch and
我曾白手起家创办公司，也
backed many more. And there's a blind
投资过许多其他公司。
spot that I keep seeing in early stage
我发现早期
founders. They spend very little time
创业者身上存在一个盲点。 他们很少花时间
thinking about HR. And it's not because
考虑人力资源问题。 这并非因为
they're reckless or they don't care.
他们鲁莽或漠不关心。
It's because they're obsessed with
这是因为他们一心想
building their companies, and I can't
发展自己的公司，这一点我不能
fault them for that. At that stage,
责怪他们。 到了那个阶段，
you're thinking about the product. How
你考虑的是产品。 如何
to attract new customers, how to grow
吸引新客户，如何发展壮大
your team, really, how to survive. and
团队，实际上，如何生存下去。
HR slips down the list because it
人力资源事务往往会被放在优先级较低的位置，因为它
doesn't feel urgent, but sooner or later
感觉并不紧急，但迟早都会变得紧急
it is. And when things get messy, tools
。 当事情变得一团糟时，
like our sponsor today, Just Works, go
像我们今天的赞助商 Just Works 这样的工具，就
from being a nice to have to being a
从锦上添花了变成了
necessity. Something goes sideways, and
必不可少。 事情出了岔子，
you find yourself having conversations
你发现自己陷入了
you did not see coming. This is when you
意想不到的对话中。 这时你才会
learn that HR really is the
明白，人力资源部门才是
infrastructure of your company, and
公司的真正基础设施，
without it, things wobble. And Just Work
没有它，公司就会摇摇欲坠。 而Just Work
stops you learning this the hard way. It
可以避免你通过痛苦的教训来学习这一点。 它可以
takes care of the stuff that would
处理那些原本会
otherwise drain your energy and your
消耗你精力和
time, automating payroll, health
时间的事情，例如自动处理工资、医疗
insurance benefits, and it gives your
保险福利，并且随时为你的
team human support at any hour. It grows
团队提供人工支持。 它会
with your small business from startup
伴随您的小企业从创业到
through growth, even when you start
发展壮大而成长，即使您开始在
hiring team members abroad. So, if you
国外招聘团队成员也是如此。 所以，如果您
want HR support that's there through the
想要在
exciting times and the challenging
激动人心的时刻和充满挑战的
times, head to justworks.com now. That's
时刻都能获得人力资源支持，请立即访问 justworks.com。 那是
just.com.
just.com。   在
story of many things we've discussed,
我们讨论过的许多事情中，比如
money, investing, building businesses
金钱、投资、创业等等，其中一个重要的主角
now is this thing called artificial
就是
intelligence which you mentioned
你之前提到的人工智能
earlier. Yes.
。 是的。   就像
It's like entered the room.
走进了房间一样。   是的
Yes.
。
And it's changing lots of these
它正在
equations in a really profound way.
以一种非常深刻的方式改变许多这样的等式。
Again, for that person who is maybe at
再说一遍，对于那些可能正处于
the start of their career or even, you
职业生涯起步阶段的人，或者甚至是
know, they're they're a lawyer right
现在是一名律师的人来说
now.
。
How are you thinking about AI? What
你对人工智能有什么看法？
should they be thinking about? Because I
他们应该考虑些什么？ 因为我
don't think we've seen something quite
觉得我们以前从未见过这样的事情
like this. Not certainly not in my
。 在我
lifetime. I've not seen disruption of
有生之年肯定不会有这样的机会。 我从未见过如此
this scale. I wasn't around for the com
大规模的混乱局面。 我没经历过互联网
boom. I was too when I was 10 or
泡沫时期。 我十岁左右的时候也是这样
something. I was eight.
。 我当时八岁。   是的
Yeah.
。
So, so how should we be thinking about
那么，我们应该如何看待
this moment? Is it a huge opportunity
这一刻呢？ 这是一个
for wealth creation or
创造财富的巨大机会吗？是的
Yeah, it's immense. It's bigger than the
，机会非常巨大。 它比互联网还要庞大
internet. And I'll tell you why. I want
。 我会告诉你为什么。 我想
to keep it down to earth. Uh because um
保持务实。 呃，因为
I'm actually using it now in use cases.
我现在确实在实际应用中使用它。
There's every sector of the economy,
经济的各个领域、
every aspect of research, every aspect
研究的各个方面、
of business has a huge opportunity here.
商业的各个方面都蕴藏着巨大的机遇。
But let's just take use cases that you
但我们只举一些你
would understand, everybody listening
能理解、所有听众
would understand.
都能理解的使用案例。
In today's post pandemic world,
在后疫情时代，
most businesses have developed large and
大多数企业都制定了规模
small direct to consumer strategies
不一的直接面向消费者的战略，
where they try and build relationships
试图
with customers and sell them product
与客户建立关系并直接向他们销售产品
direct. Yeah, they still use retail. Say
。 是的，他们仍然采用零售模式。 就说
you're Nike or something. And um you you
你是耐克之类的吧。 嗯，在
before the pandemic. You're now 50%. And
疫情之前，你们的直接面向消费者的比例是 27%。 你现在已经完成了50%。
direct to consumer gets you higher
直接面向消费者可以带来更高的
margins, but it also gets you data. Gets
利润，同时也能让你获得数据。 它可以让
you information about the preferences of
你了解
your customer base. What they like, what
客户群的偏好。 他们喜欢什么，
they don't like, the flavors, and what
不喜欢什么，喜欢什么口味，买什么，什么时候
they buy, when they buy, where they buy
买，在哪里买
it, all that stuff. And it's very
，所有这些信息。
interesting that data. And let me give
这些数据非常有趣。 我举
you an example. Wine business. If you
个例子。 葡萄酒行业。 想想
the wine business, the challenge of a
葡萄酒行业，一个有着
thousand-y old business, you don't know
千年历史的行业所面临的挑战，你永远无法预知
what the weather's going to be like. you
天气会如何。 你
don't know what varietals to to to grow
不知道该种植哪些品种，
because you don't know what the
因为你不知道
preference of the customer is because
顾客的喜好，因为
you're selling it through multiple tiers
你是通过多层
of distribution. During the pandemic, 43
分销渠道销售的。 疫情期间，
states in America opened up direct to
美国 43 个州开放了
consumer sales from the wineries in the
西海岸酒庄直接向消费​​者销售葡萄酒的渠道
West Coast. For the first time ever, the
。 酒庄有史以来第一次
wineries found out, what people buy,
了解到，人们购买什么酒，在
where they buy it, when they buy it,
哪里购买，何时购买，
what they drink, what varietals. And I'm
喝什么酒，以及他们喜欢哪些品种。 我
in the wine business. I sell three
从事葡萄酒行业。 我每年销售三
million bottles a year of wine. One of
百万瓶葡萄酒。
my companies, actually, a Shark Tank
实际上，我的一家公司，一家参加过《创智赢家》（Shark Tank）节目的
company. Um, and we partner with a
公司。 嗯，我们与一家
company called uh QVC. We sell online
名为 QVC 的公司合作。 我们通过网络销售，
and and so I can tell you today,
所以我可以告诉你，今天、
this month, this week, the number one
这个月、这周，
varietal in Southern Florida for women
南佛罗里达州
ages 44 to 64 is Mosscato, a sweet wine.
44 至 64 岁女性最受欢迎的葡萄酒品种是莫斯卡托，一种甜葡萄酒。
I think it tastes like [__] I don't
我觉得它味道像屎一样。 我不在乎自己
care what I think. It's the number one
怎么想。 它现在是排名第一的
wine right now. And I knew that to to
葡萄酒。 我知道，为了
right place at the right time to support
满足
that demand for the rest of this summer.
今年夏季剩余时间的需求，我必须在六个月前就推出这个品种，这样我才能及时发货，并将库存和资本支出放在合适的地方。
A sweet cold Mosscato wine. That means I
一款冰镇的甜莫斯卡托葡萄酒。 这意味着我
spent a lot less money, a lot less risk.
花的钱少得多，承担的风险也小得多。
want this summer. I have exactly what
今年夏天，我这里没有他们不想要的品种。 我正好有
they want. That was AI.
他们想要的东西。 那是人工智能。
It cost me virtually nothing to get that
获取这些数据几乎没花我一分钱
data. Five, 10 years ago, it would have
。 五到十年前，
cost me a million bucks to go do all the
要做所有这些市场调查，我需要花费一百万美元
market research. I got that for $18,000.
。 我花了18000美元买下了它。   这
So that's using an AI tool. Here's
就是使用人工智能工具。 再举
another example. So do I use that tool?
一个例子。 那我该用那个工具吗？
100%. And there's many tools. You don't
100%。 而且有很多工具。 你不一定
have to just use chat. There's many
要用聊天功能。 有很多
different competing platforms. So we use
不同的竞争平台。 所以我们都用上了
them all. We check the assumptions by
。 我们通过
checking it all on all of them. See the
对所有假设进行全面检查来验证这些假设。 注意这些
little variances. Number two, I have to
细微的差别。 第二，我得
shoot an ad. I have to shoot a
拍个广告。 我要拍个
commercial.
广告。
I'm going to shoot it here in LA. I'm
我打算在洛杉矶拍摄。 我打算
going to do it in a studio like this
在像这样的摄影棚里，
with a green screen. And um I'm going to
用绿幕来完成这项工作。 嗯，我打算花
spend, you know, $250,000 for a 30, you
25 万美元，从同一组照片中拍摄 30 张照片，你
know, 15, a 30, and a 60 out of the same
知道，还有 15 张照片、30 张照片和 60 张照片
shoot. And I'm then going to go into
。 然后我打算
post with the green screen and I'm going
用绿幕进行后期处理，并且会
to spend more money in post. I'm going
在后期制作上投入更多资金。 我会
to add whatever I need, whatever
添加我需要的任何内容，任何
background I'm going to need. Or I could
我需要的背景信息。 或者我可以
fly to Dubai
飞去迪拜，
where they have a giant studio with a 6K
那里有一个巨大的工作室，配备 6K
digital wall
数字墙，
where AI links up your script
人工智能可以将你的剧本
to the background. There is no
与背景连接起来。 没有
post-prouction. You basically shoot the
后期制作。 基本上，你只需要
in 4 hours and it's done. The
4个小时就能拍完这条广告，然后就完成了。
background's perfect. The imagery is
背景完美。 画面
perfect. Your script is perfect. And I
完美。 你的剧本完美无瑕。 我
did that two weeks ago for the first
两周前第一次做了这件事
time. I'd never seen that before. We did
。 我以前从未见过这种情况。 我们用的成本仅为
in post-prouction. But then I'll tell
后期制作中采用传统方法所需成本的一小部分。 但接下来我要告诉
you what freaked me out.
你什么事吓到我了。
They reshot the commercial without me
他们没有我
there using Kevin agent
在场，而是用 Kevin Agent 和
an AI view.
AI 视角重新拍摄了广告。
I wasn't even there. and just to show
我当时根本不在场。 而这仅仅是为了证明，
that they could produce a new commercial
他们可以用 9000 美元制作出一个背景相同的全新广告，而
that would have cost 400,000 from
从零开始制作则需要 40 万美元
scratch. So there's going to be a lot of
。 所以，那将会造成很多
job disruption then because as you said
工作上的混乱，因为正如你所说，
you don't say but on the other hand I've
你不会说，但另一方面，我
now got content for that particular
现在有了为那家特定
business I was shooting that you know
企业拍摄的内容，你知道，
I've got content for that particular
我有为那家特定
business I was going to shoot that
企业拍摄
commercial for and I said guys
广告的内容，我说伙计们，
let's tweak it and shoot it again. He
我们修改一下再拍一次。 他
said yeah we'll do it in two seconds.
说，好的，我们两秒钟之内就能完成。
We'll send you the the 15 seconds back.
我们会把15秒前的视频发给你。
I said I I I don't like what I said
我说过我不喜欢我刚才说的话
there. Can I change what I said? Yeah.
。 我可以更改我之前说的话吗？ 是的。
Well do you want it in Spanish? You want
你想听西班牙语的吗？ 你想要
it in Japanese? You want it in Arabic?
日语版的吗？ 你想要阿拉伯语的吗？
That's the power. The productivity that
这就是力量。 接下来，
we're going to get, we're going to our
我们的生产力将会下降，我们用于
budgets for producing content are going
内容制作的预算、
and software and everything else, right?
软件以及其他所有方面的支出都将大幅减少，对吧？
Now, full circle to your your thing
现在，一切都将回归正轨，回到你之前提到的
about the chips that all came from
芯片问题，这些芯片都来自
Nvidia chips
英伟达芯片，
that not that's not from Chinese chips.
而不是来自中国芯片。
Whoever controls the chip and the
控制芯片和
honeybees that the honey bees are those
蜜蜂的人，也就是蜜蜂的制造者，
guys are all Indians and Pakistanis.
都是印度人和巴基斯坦人。
They're genius mathematicians. That's
他们是天才数学家。
the team over there running off that
那边那个团队就是在用那个
platform. If we had let anyways I don't
平台运作的。 如果我们放任不管，我也不想那样，
want to I'm just freaked out that we got
我只是很害怕我们必须
to control that. We we need democracy to
控制这件事。 我们需要民主来
control that.
控制这种情况。
Your children, what are you saying to
你对你的孩子们说了些什么，
them though about their professional
关于他们
ambitions in a world where creating
在当今世界里的职业抱负，比如创造
stuff like that and you know whether
诸如此类的东西，还有你想让
it's who do you want to do your your
谁来帮你
taxes an accountant or an AI? Who do you
报税——是会计师还是人工智能？ 你想让谁来帮你
want to do your legal documents? Who do
办理法律文件？
you want to do your any sort of like
你想让谁来帮你做任何类似
white collar job your make your videos
白领的工作，比如制作视频和
edit your videos? I I tell them, you
剪辑视频？ 我告诉他们，你
know, everybody's got a lot of angst
知道，每个人都对人工智能有很多担忧
with AI. I I tell them, listen,
。 我告诉他们，听着，
everybody chillax. It's a tool. You
大家都放松点。 它是一种工具。 你
know, it's the same classic thing where
知道，这跟以前人们认为
radio was going to be displaced by
广播会被
television. Radio's bigger than it ever
电视取代的情况很像。 广播的规模比以往任何时候都大
has been. It it just it doesn't matter.
。 但这无关紧要。
The one thing I concern myself with with
我最关心的
AI is warfare. And I think the country
人工智能应用领域是战争。 我认为，
that has the best AI and data centers
拥有最好的人工智能和数据中心
and the most advanced chip technology
以及最先进的芯片技术的国家
will win the wars of the future, which
将在未来
will be fought by drones and robots. I
由无人机和机器人进行的战争中获胜。 我
know that sounds kind of crazy.
知道这听起来有点疯狂。
No, it doesn't sound crazy. That's where
不，这听起来并不疯狂。 事情
it's happening now.
现在就发生在那里。   它最终会
That's where it's going to go. So, so
去那里。 所以，
when I when I solicit the ear of a
当我试图向
senator, I try and explain to them my
参议员们解释我关于蜜蜂的比喻时，我会试着向他们
honeybee analogy saying this is about
说明这关乎
defense. I don't want to live under
防御。 我不想生活在
authoritarian. You know, I know we
独裁统治下。 我知道，如今我们都在
debate the whole political environment
讨论整个政治环境
these days, but I don't want to live
，但我不想生活在
around Chinese honey. I just don't. And
中国蜂蜜的包围中。 我就是不明白。 而
those are going to be the two
它们将成为两大
superpowers. You both you're in one
超级大国。 你们俩都在同一条
vertical. Either you let the Chinese
垂直线上。 要么让中国人用
make the honey on AI or we make the
人工智能生产蜂蜜，要么我们生产
honey and let the Chinese buy some honey
蜂蜜，然后让中国人
from us. I know where I want to live. I
从我们这里购买蜂蜜。 我知道我想住在哪里。 我
know what I want to do. And I think I
知道自己想做什么。 我认为我
can convince a lot of senators the same
可以说服很多参议员接受同样的
idea because you got to understand the
观点，因为你们必须理解
Wnjak jobs analogy that we that you
我们之前提出的 Wnjak 就业类比
brought out earlier. That was the genius
。 这就是
of jobs. Make the honey but know who the
就业的精妙之处。 酿造蜂蜜，但要知道谁
queen bee is.
是蜂后。
The genius of jobs brings me to a
乔布斯的天才之处让我想到一个
question I've wanted to ask someone like
我一直想问像你这样的人的问题：
you for a long long time which is do you
你
think Apple is dead?
认为苹果公司已经死了吗？   不，
No. No you don't.
你不需要。
No. I'll tell you why. I'll tell you
不，我来告诉你为什么。 我来告诉你
why. You know it's so interesting. uh
为什么。 你知道这很有趣吗？ 呃，
people don't understand the genius of
人们不理解苹果的精髓，
Apple because this is again came from
因为这又源于
Jobs you know he used to say to my team
乔布斯。你知道，他过去常常对我的团队说，就像
over and over again and I mentioned it
我
earlier they don't know what they want
之前提到的那样，他们不知道自己想要什么，
until I tell them
直到我告诉他们。
and I always just just as close as you
我总是像你
and I are right now you're Steve
我一样亲近。史蒂夫，你
say Steve
说，史蒂夫，
how the [__] do you know that how do you
你怎么知道
know that you don't know that you don't
你不知道你不
know what you don't No. He said, "Show
知道什么？不，他说：“告诉
me where I'm wrong. Show me one instance
我我哪里错了。告诉我一个
of us working together. I'm wrong." I
我们合作的例子。我错了。” 我
said, "It hasn't happened yet, Steve.
说：“史蒂夫，还没发生呢，
Doesn't mean it won't.
不代表以后不会发生。
Get back to work. Don't worry about it.
回去工作吧，别担心，我会
I'll worry about it. You make the
担心的。你负责
software. I have the chips. Make the
软件，我负责芯片。你负责
software. Go make the honey. I have the
软件，我负责蜂蜜，我负责
queen bee. Don't worry about it." And
蜂后。别担心。”
that
这
is pretty interesting because you got to
很有意思，因为你必须
prove it that he was wrong. Let's take
证明他错了。 让我们
let's accelerate. He's dead now. But the
加速吧。 他已经死了。 但
philosophy of Apple and I'll give you
苹果的理念，我会告诉你，
the the way you win at you look at it. I
你如何才能成功，从你的角度来看。 我
can go buy a $330 laptop right here
可以在这里花 330 美元买到一台
with the same processing power of this
和这台
$1,800 Mac laptop.
1800 美元的 Mac 笔记本电脑处理能力相同的笔记本电脑。
Why would I been spend 1,800 when I
我为什么要花1800美元买
could buy this for 300? Why brand? I
这个，而我只需要300美元就能买到呢？ 为什么要打造品牌？ 我
want to be part of this universe.
想成为这个宇宙的一部分。
This honey right over here, the Apple
这里的蜂蜜，Apple
Care, the fact that the OS works on all
Care，操作系统可以在所有平台上运行，
the platforms and the messages are shown
而且信息可以
on all platforms simultaneously. All the
在所有平台上同时显示。 所有的
OS, all the honey,
操作系​​统，所有的蜂蜜，
that platform is the power of brand.
这个平台就是品牌的力量。
It's I'm not leaving this universe and
我不会离开这个世界，而
Apple is one of the world's largest
苹果是世界上最大的
companies. And you may say, "Oh, an
公司之一。 你可能会说：“哦，一项
innovation is going to make everybody
创新会让所有人都
leave that platform." I don't think so.
离开那个平台。” 我不这么认为。
They let other people sometimes bring in
他们有时会允许其他人开拓
a new market and then they take it over.
新市场，然后再将其接管。
And I saw Steve do that multiple times.
我亲眼看到史蒂夫多次这样做。
He did it um with the phone. I was
他用手机做的。 我当时就在
around for that. That was crazy. I mean,
现场。 太疯狂了。 我的意思是，
he had the vision that we would someday
他预见到我们将来会
run our software on the phone. I said,
在手机上运行我们的软件。 我说：
"You're out of your mind. The screen's
“你疯了吧。屏幕
too small." He said, "No,
太小了。” 他说：“不，
you're going to go vertical. You're
你要走垂直路线。你
going to rewrite all this crap
要把所有这些垃圾都
vertically."
垂直重写一遍。”
I mean, I can't fault him on anything.
我的意思是，我挑不出他任何毛病。
Although I kept telling him, "You're
虽然我一直告诉他：“你
going to get it wrong one day. You're
总有一天会犯错。你
not going to be right all the time." I
不可能永远都对。” 我
can't find when he wasn't right. That
找不到他什么时候做错了。 这就是令人
that's that's the frustration because I
沮丧的地方，因为我
teach this you know to a har bunch of
教的是一群
really smart kids at Harvard of which by
哈佛大学非常聪明的学生，其中
the way a third are international
三分之一是国际
students and
学生，
they say well when did you catch him? I
他们会问：“你是什么时候抓住他的？” 我
said he didn't
说他不知道，
what was he doing was did he have a
他当时在做什么？他是否有某种
practice or or principles that allowed
方法或原则让
him to see around the corner? He spent a
他能够预见未来？ 他晚上花了
lot of time at night um
很多时间，
you know
你知道，
even studying fonts and looking at art
甚至研究字体、欣赏艺术，
and um focusing on the signal. I think
以及专注于信号。 我觉得
his wife talked about that a lot. He I
他妻子经常谈到这件事。 我的
mean she spent more time with him than
意思是，她和他相处的时间比和任何人都多
anybody else. Although W talks about a
。 虽然W谈论了
lot because those guys spent countless
很多，因为那些人​​一起度过了无数个
hours together and
小时，
but but
但
Jobs defined
乔布斯定义说，
he would take
他会
instances from nature
从自然界
into his head or from Japanese,
或日本，
you know, scripture or text or imagery
你知道，经文、文本或图像中汲取灵感，
and redefine it into technology in a way
并以其他人从未做过的方式将其重新定义为技术
that no one else was doing. And that's
。 这就是
the idea of the honey and the bee and
蜂蜜、蜜蜂、蜂后
the queen and all that stuff. It kind of
以及所有相关事物的由来。 这在某种程度上
comes from his view of the world. And I
源于他的世界观。 我
don't know if you can understand this,
不知道你是否能理解，
but because it was so
但正因为
it came from nature, it was easy for
它源于自然，所以
people to assimilate it. It wasn't
人们很容易接受它。 它不是
foreign. When they looked at the imagery
外国的。 当他们审视图像
and the design, he he tried to pull from
和设计时，他试图从
from pleasing images from nature like
自然界中令人愉悦的图像中汲取灵感，例如
the fonts on the first Max. I remember
第一代 Max 上的字体。 我记得
when we were writing the code for that
当时我们在编写那个代码的时候，我
saying, "Steve, this is not what people
说：“史蒂夫，这不是人们
are used to seeing on a computer
在电脑屏幕上通常看到的东西
screen." He said, "No, it isn't. That's
。” 他说：“不，并非如此。正因如此，
why it's going to work." He, if you
它才会奏效。”
think about the very first scalable
想想最早的可缩放
fonts,
字体，
I saw that first. And I said, "See, this
我第一个就看到了。 我说：“你看，
is this is almost foreign." He said,
这几乎是外国的。” 他说：
"Well, how's it make you feel?" I said,
“那你感觉如何？” 我说：
"Makes me feel pretty good. This looks
“这让我感觉很好。这看起来
like it's on a piece of paper. If you I
像是写在纸上的。如果你
don't you weren't even born when this
不知道，我猜你出生的时候这些
stuff was happening but it was it he was
事还没发生，但事实就是如此，他当时
so far ahead
遥遥领先，
and this is the same way Elon is
埃隆·马斯克也在以同样的方式
redefining whether it's you know SpaceX
重新定义一切，无论是SpaceX，
or whether it's what he's doing in
还是他在
neurosurgery or Tesla or you know all of
神经外科领域所做的工作，或是特斯拉，或者你知道的所有
these initiatives uh you know his
这些项目，比如他的
satellite technologies they are the same
卫星技术，都是一样的。
those guys except you know Elon's 100%
除了埃隆·马斯克的100%
signal I said that earlier they are the
信号（我之前说过），他们都是
same and they should be their treasures,
一样的，他们应该成为他们的瑰宝，
their national treasures. It doesn't
他们的国家瑰宝。
matter if you like them. It doesn't
你是否喜欢他们并不重要，
matter what their politics are is
他们的政治立场也无关紧要，重要的是
irrelevant the contributions they're
他们
making to society and to America,
对社会和美国所做的贡献，
frankly, and the competitive competitive
坦白说，以及
nature of of of countries. That's why I
国家之间的竞争本质。这就是为什么我
thought it was so important that Trump
认为特朗普
make up with Elon. The the most powerful
与埃隆·马斯克和解如此重要。地球上最有权势的
man on earth should have a a very good
人应该
relationship with the most the richest
与地球上最富有的
man on earth because he's the largest
人保持良好的关系，因为他是
industrialist on earth. Maybe there's
地球上最大的实业家。也许吧。” 就像他们因为
them being who you just said they are
你刚才说的他们是
the most powerful.
最有权势的人而产生的一种与生俱来的无能为力。
But they know they're smart enough to
但他们知道自己足够聪明，能够
know. It's the same way I felt about
明白这一点。我对乔布斯的感觉也一样
Jobs. I'm getting back on the plane this
。这季度我又要坐飞机回去了
quarter. I know he's going to beat me
。我知道他会揍我
up, but it doesn't matter. It It's the
，但这不重要。
greater good is that we get this
重要的是我们能把这个
software out there advancing ma math and
软件推向市场，提高学生的数学和
reading scores.
阅读成绩。
Was he happy, Steve?
他快乐吗，史蒂夫？
I don't know the answer to that
我不知道
question.
答案。
Do you think he was a happy person?
你觉得他是个快乐的人吗？
I don't know. He I've never I never saw
我不知道。我从来没见过
him happy. He was always barking at me.
他快乐。他总是对我大吼大叫。
I never saw him happy. I don't think I
我从没见过他快乐。我想我从来没
ever saw him laugh.
见过他笑。
I don't He may not have been, you know,
他可能不是那种……你知道，我的
that I mean that's probably something
意思是，这可能只有
his wife would know, but he looked like
他妻子知道，但我觉得他看起来像个
a tortured guy to me, but um
饱受折磨的人，嗯，
you know that may have been his curse. I
你知道，这或许是他的诅咒。
you know some some you
你知道……
do you love him?
你爱他吗？
Yeah,
是的，
I can see it in your face
我百分之百能从你的脸上看出来
100%. I saw a lot of emotion in your
。我看到了很多。
face the first time you spoke about him
你第一次谈到他的时候，脸上就流露出情绪，
and I thought that's surprising for
我觉得这对于一个曾经对
someone that barked at you.
你大吼大叫的人来说很不可思议。
Well, he respected me, that's for sure.
嗯，他确实尊重我。
He wouldn't execute on my ideas. He
他不会采纳我的想法，他
expected me to execute on his, but he
希望我执行他的想法，但他
was never wrong.
从未出错。你的
Where did the emotions stem from?
情绪从何而来？
Oh, you know, it brings me back into
哦，你知道，这让我想起了
that room with Heidi Rosen and all the
和海蒂·罗森在同一个房间里，以及所有那些
crazy crap. I mean, it was just nuts.
疯狂的事情。我的意思是，那简直太疯狂了。
And you know, the you know, I'd have to
你知道，我得花
spend a lot of time. The only the only
很多时间才能想清楚。
meeting I really remember um the the one
我真正记得的唯一一次会议，嗯，
that's really sticks in my mind when we
真正让我印象深刻的一次，是
were in Certino and we were just I think
在切尔蒂诺，我们当时好像在争取
18 million or something and Heidi was
1800万美元之类的，海蒂
there.
也在。
Who's Heidi? Heidi Rosen. Um, she's a
海蒂是谁？海蒂·罗森。嗯，她是一位
famous um, venture capitalist, but she
著名的风险投资家，但她
was also kind of the muse, the person
也算是乔布斯的灵感缪斯，是那个
that could actually deal with Jobs all
能在
day long at Apple and bring him back to
苹果公司整天和乔布斯周旋，并在
Earth when he was out of his mind. I'll
他失去理智时把他拉回现实的人。我会…… 给
give you an example of how that would
你举个例子，说明这会如何
work. And I've seen her since, you know,
运作。从那以后我就没见过她了，你知道，
it's it's it's I don't even know if she
我甚至不知道她是否还
remembers this particular. Anyways, we
记得这件事。总之，我们
leave. He's barking at me. He's and he's
离开了。他冲我狂吠。他把
got one of my product managers in tears
我的一个产品经理弄哭了，
because she wanted to do the market
因为她想做市场
research and he said, "No way. I we're
调研，但他却说：“不行。”  “我们只会听
just going to do what I say." And she
我的。”她
just felt like her job was useless. And
觉得自己的工作毫无意义。
and for him it was. I mean, he just
对他来说确实如此。我的意思是，他根本
didn't give a [__] what she thought.
不在乎她的想法。
Although she ran the universe of the
尽管她负责《
Oregon Trail or something. It's a
俄勒冈之旅》之类的游戏。那可是个
massive title, like a huge multi-million
大作，一款价值数百万
dollar title on the Mac in every 110,000
美元的Mac游戏，在美国每11万所
schools in America.
学校里都有。
And he he was so pissed that you know in
他气疯了，你知道，在
these old buildings they have the little
那些老建筑里，
window where you have a little knob and
窗户很小，有个小旋钮，
it only opens up four inches so you
只能打开四英寸，所以你
can't jump out of it in a hotel or
不可能从酒店之
something. So we were we had a Herz
类的地方跳出去。当时我们租了一辆赫兹的车，
rental and we're the whole team's going
整个团队都要
out. I'm going to drive the car back to
出去。我要开车回
Boston and he he undoes the window and
旧金山，然后飞回波士顿。他打开窗户，结果
he's got his head stuck and there's
头卡住了，冲着
yelling at me from from
我大喊大叫。
I'm looking up at him saying, you know,
我抬头看着他，心想：搞什么鬼？什么？你还要什么？
more can we we you already kicked us
你都把我们赶
out, you know? And then on the way, we
出去了，你懂吗？ 路上，我们用的是
had these old brick the earliest cell
那种老式的砖头手机，最早的那种手机
phones, these brick phones. Heidi calls
，就是那种笨重的砖头手机。海蒂打电话给
me, says, "Okay, he'll do it for 12
我说：“好吧，他愿意出
million." I said, "Heidi, why do we have
1200万。”我说：“海蒂，我们为什么要
to go through all that [__] Like, why
经历这些破事？”  “比如，
do we even have to get abused?" She
我们为什么要遭受虐待？”她
said, "Why is the sky blue?" you know,
说，“为什么天空是蓝色的？”你知道，
just get back on the plane and go do it.
就回到飞机上继续做下去。
It was a huge hit. Like it just, you
这首歌非常火爆。你
know, it's a huge hit. Like it's just
知道，它就是非常火爆。就像，
the guy was if you looked at it like uh
如果你仔细想想，呃，他，他
he he he could he could write the hit
能写出热门
songs. That's what he did. He write the
歌曲。他就是这么做的。他写出了
hit songs. So you don't even if you hate
热门歌曲。所以，即使你讨厌
the producer, you want the the guy that
制作人，你也想要那个
can do the hit songs, right? If you're
能写出热门歌曲的人，对吧？如果你是
an artist, you put up with a crazy
一个艺术家，你就得忍受一个疯狂的
producer.
制作人。他难道就不能友善一点吗？
Could he not have been nice? Do you
你
think?
觉得呢？
Not in his DNA.
他的基因里就没有这种特质。
No. Do you think if he he was a nice
不。你觉得如果他是一个友善的
person he wouldn't
人，他不会……
you know what he would say about that
你知道他会怎么说吗？
that's noise
那都是噪音，他根本不在乎，是的，
he gives a [__]
他根本
yeah he doesn't give a [__] noise being
不在乎噪音，对他来说，
nice is noise that for him I mean we
友善就是噪音。我的意思是，我们
spent a lot of time talking about him
花了很多时间谈论他，
but I think there's a lot of lessons
但我认为我们可以
learned from him that I think managers
从他身上学到很多东西，我认为今天的经理人、
today parents today certainly CEOs today
今天的父母，当然还有今天的CEO们，
uh you know you're you're about this
呃，你知道的，你们…… 你提到的这个
show is about CEOs um
节目是关于CEO的，嗯，
I wish every CEO had spent the time the
我希望每位CEO都能像我一样，花那么多时间与
minimal time that I spent with jobs had
乔布斯相处。哪怕只是短暂的相处，也
such an impact on me. I mean, it it I I
对我产生了如此深远的影响。我的意思是，
I owe a lot of my success to him because
我的成功很大程度上要归功于他，因为
I think I always think, what would Steve
我总是会想，如果史蒂夫在世，他会怎么
have done?
做？
And I make decisions like that. It's
然后我就会按照他的想法做决定。这太
amazing. The guy's still around. I bet
不可思议了。他现在依然活跃在人们的视野中。我敢打赌，
you if you talk to, you know, any of the
如果你和
management at Apple, they they have that
苹果公司的任何一位管理层交谈，他们
ghost in those rooms for sure,
肯定都能感受到他的存在，
including the current CEO who I think
包括现任CEO，我认为他
was doing a phenomenal job. He he spent
做得非常出色。他曾
so many hours with Jobs. He knows
与乔布斯共事无数个小时。他
exactly what I'm talking about.
完全明白我的意思。
that guy for sure.
毫无疑问，没有人比他更深入地了解商业。
I asked you a second ago if Steve Jobs
我刚才问过你，史蒂夫·乔布斯
was happy, but are you happy?
是否快乐，那么你快乐吗？
I get happier the older I get because um
我越老越快乐，因为……
I've I'm very comfortable. I found a
我感觉很自在。我找到了一个……
place um you know uh that I'm and I this
你知道，……
may be just what aging does. I mean, it
也许这就是衰老带来的结果。我的意思是，
just, you know, in and when I was in my
你知道，在我
30s, I had a lot of trauma and turmoil
30多岁的时候…… 我经历了很多创伤和动荡，
and and just, you know, um hard time to
你知道，那段时间很难
find trying to figure out who I was. And
找到自我。
I also suffered from dyslexia, which
我还患有阅读障碍，现在
I've come to think of as a superpower
我把它看作是一种超能力，而
now, not an affliction, but it it was
不是一种缺陷。但就像你
kind of like it's hard to know what
很难知道
journey you're going to be on until you
自己要走哪条路，直到你
find it. And then I found it, and then I
找到它。然后我找到了，然后我
started on a new journey. and and
开始了新的旅程。
you know it's um
你知道，这就像
it's something where you know you ask
你
yourself every day goes by and you know
每天都在问自己，
this the noise and signal thing and how
这就是所谓的“噪音和信号”的问题，今天我有
much of this day was I happy doing the
多少时间是快乐地做自己想做的事情？如果
happy if if I measure it by
我用“今天
is there anything that I spend my time
我有没有做任何
doing that I don't want to do today the
我不想做的事情”来衡量，我会非常快乐，
answer is no because I don't have do and
因为我没有非做不可的事情，
so I don't waste my time. I do, you
所以我不会浪费时间。你
know, even coming here to spend two
知道，即使是来这里
hours with you. When I first, you know,
和你待两个小时。当我第一次
heard about it, I went online and said,
听说这件事的时候，我上网查了一下，然后说：
"Oh, yeah. This guy, this guy's great.
“哦，是的。” 这家伙，这家伙太棒了。
I'd love to work with him." You know,
我很乐意和他一起工作。”你知道，就是
that kind of thing.
那种感觉。
You you allocate your time. This is this
你要合理安排时间。这就是
is I'm happy to do this. I want to be
我乐意做的事。我想待在
here. And I think, you know, we had a
这里。而且我觉得，你知道，我们
very interesting couple hours together.
一起度过了非常愉快的几个小时。
But that's the definition of happiness.
这就是幸福的定义。
What concerns me, and my wife often says
我担心的是，我妻子经常
to me, "We don't need any more money.
对我说：“我们不需要更多的钱了。”
Why are why are you flying 300 hours a
你为什么每年要乘坐飞机飞行 300 小时
year on an airplane? What are you
？ 你在
doing?"
做什么？
I said, "I'm happy." Like,
我说：“我很开心。”
you know, I'm I'm happy doing this. I
你知道，我做这些事很开心。我
want to do this stuff. You know, I
想做这些事。你知道，我
sometimes I do five cities in a day.
有时候一天能去五个城市。
It's freaking crazy. And it's the
简直太疯狂了。这就是
travel today. You can do that. But it's
如今航空旅行的妙处。你可以做到。但这对
it's sport for you. It's it's it's so
我来说就像运动一样。这太
interesting. I get so many interesting
有趣了。我得到了很多有趣的
opportunities. I can't turn them down.
机会。我无法拒绝它们。
They're just such,
它们就是如此，
you know.
你知道。
Are you driven or are you dragged? You
你是被驱动还是被拖着？你
know, you use the word trauma there. And
知道，你用了“创伤”这个词。
I often ask myself that question because
我经常问自己这个问题，因为
I I came from a all-white area. I was
我来自一个全是白人的地区。我是个
the black kid with the strange hair and
黑人小孩，有着奇怪的发型和
the strange family. I was insecure. And
奇怪的家庭。我缺乏安全感。
I think that resulted in this this force
我认为正是这种不安全感造就了我强大的
of will to try and correct the
意志力，让我努力克服这种不
insecurity or to prove something to
安全感，或者向自己证明些什么，
myself which then resulted in success. I
最终获得了成功。我
I think there is no drag. There's only
认为没有拖着，只有
driven. I don't understand being
驱动。我不理解被
dragged. Dragged insinuates that you
拖着。被拖着意味着你
don't care about performance. You don't
不…… 你只关心业绩，
care whether you succeed or not. You're
不在乎成败，只是被成功
just being sucked into the void of
的虚空吞噬
success. You might be able to say that
。你或许会对一首
for a rock star that gets a hit song,
热门歌曲的摇滚明星这么说，
but um most of them doesn't last. I you
但大多数热门歌曲都昙花一现。你
need massive amounts of of drive. And I
需要强大的动力。我
love the most the most exciting thing I
最喜欢、最激动人心的事情
like to do is when someone tells me
就是当有人告诉我
you can't do that like watch insurance.
你做不到某件事，比如手表保险。他们说
You will never launch a watch insurance
你永远不可能创办一家手表
company. It you will never do that. You
保险公司，永远不可能做到，永远不可能
will never get around the compliance
绕过各州的合规要求，永远不可能
state by state. You will never launch in
在
the Middle East. You'll never launch in
中东开展业务，永远不可能在
England. [__] That's exactly what I
英国开展业务。胡说八道！我就是这么做的
did. I found the right team. I found the
。我找到了合适的团队，找到了
right partners. I figured it out. I I
合适的合作伙伴，我找到了解决办法，我对它
was passionate about it. And I think I'm
充满热情。我认为我会大获成功
going to kick ass. I think I'm I think
。我认为
in two or three years from now you won't
两三年后，你们就
be able to catch up with me. That's what
追不上我了。我是这么
I think.
认为的。
I'm 32 years old. What What is the
我今年32岁。
advice that you wish you got at 32 years
你希望在32岁时得到什么建议
old? Kevin,
？ 凯文，
what I have learned and this is
我学到的一点，也是
something that you should really think
你应该认真思考的
about for yourself.
。
Your real value, your real brand
你真正的价值，你真正的品牌，
are your followers. this army of people
就是你的粉丝。这群
that have decided to invest their time
愿意花时间关注
in you. You know, you've cut across a a
你的人，已经影响了非常
vast swath of people. So you influence
广泛的人群。你影响着
very successful managers, CEOs, and a
许多成功的经理人、CEO，
lot of young entrepreneurs want to hear
很多年轻的创业者都想听听
what you have to say because they
你的看法，因为
they're expecting you to deliver
他们期待你能提供
multiple sectors and you also have your
跨行业的宝贵信息。而且你还拥有
own data, but men and women. And so
自己的数据，涵盖男性和女性。那么，
where do you take that? Because you know
你该如何利用这些数据呢？
it's do you want to launch a clothing
你想推出服装
line? Do you want to sell burgers? Do
系列吗？你想卖汉堡吗？
you want to do consulting? You know,
你想做咨询吗？你知道，
it's it's you have all those
你有很多
opportunities, but what fits your brand?
机会，但什么才真正符合你的品牌形象？
I have and you'll get to do this. You'll
我已经做到了，你也会
get to do this. You'll be approached by
做到。你会遇到
a lot of people that want to ride that
很多想利用
network you've built. And my advice to
你建立的人脉网络的人。我的建议
you is
是，
because this has really worked for me.
因为这对我来说真的有效。想想看，
Is is this a product or service that I
这是否是我
personally would use that I would
个人会使用的产品或服务？ 我
actually use?
真的会用吗？
Because you'll get offered a lot of
因为你会收到很多
money to talk about one brand or another
钱，让你代言某个
brand. They will. And you may be weak
品牌。他们会这么做。你可能软弱地
and take it. But
接受了。但
the minute
一旦
anybody in your network, in your
你的人脉圈、你的
community thinks you're not authentic,
圈子里有人觉得你不够真诚，
you're [__]
你就完蛋了。
And you know that.
你知道的。所以
And so you better be authentic. You
你最好真诚。你最好
better be transparent. You better be
透明。你最好
honest. Even when turmoil hits, whatever
诚实。即使遇到麻烦，不管是
it's going to be, I found that saved my
什么，我发现
ass so many times by just saying,
只要说
"Here's what I know. Here's what
“我知道这些”，就能让我脱身无数次。 事情就是这样
happened." And that actually bonds them
发生的。” 这实际上让他们和
even closer to you. And and that's
你更加亲近了。而
that's the difficulty you're going to
你即将
have is how much do you want to take ne
面临的难题是，你想抓住多少机会，
because you're going to have that
因为你将拥有这样的
opportunity. But if you stay authentic
机会。但如果你保持真诚，
and say I'm going to do I'm going to
说“我要
support this brand because I use it.
支持这个品牌，因为我自己也在用”，那么
Every single brand or commission I have
我支持的每一个品牌或佣金，我都会亲自
in supporting a business I use myself.
使用。
I'm a shareholder in it and I believe in
我是它的股东，我相信
it and I use the product or you know
它，我会使用他们的产品，或者你知道，
whatever like the wines I make myself
比如我和妻子自己酿的酒，
with my wife we drink them at our family
我们会在家人面前喝，
and everybody knows that. So you
大家都知道。所以，
if it's I wouldn't drink it if it's [__]
如果是劣质酒，我是不会喝的
wine. Yeah.
。是的。
So it's it's sort of like
所以，这有点像是
that's my advice to you because I meet a
我给你的建议，因为我见过
lot of people but you're very rare. you
很多人，但你非常特别。你所
what you've built maybe by
建立的一切，也许是偶然发生的，也许是某种奇妙的
alchemy occurred, you have it now. It's
化学反应，现在你拥有了它。它就在
yours to lose. Don't [__] it up.
你的手中，别搞砸了。
No, everything you said is so true. And
不，你说的每句话都对。嗯，
um obviously the things that I uh the
显然，我 呃，
things that we talk about in the show in
我在节目里提到的那些
terms of brands that I promote, pretty
我推广的品牌，
much all of them I've invested my own
几乎都是我自己投资的
money into. Yeah.
。是的。
And this is like super important. So I
这一点非常重要。我之前也提到过
talked about my Whoop. Yeah.
我的Whoop。嗯
Um,
，
if you look at the investments I have
如果你看看我的投资
and the things I talk about, there's a
和我谈论的那些东西，你会发现
really clear through line through them.
它们之间有一条非常清晰的主线。这条
So, there's a really clear through and
主线非常清晰，
it's actually reflective of just where I
实际上反映了我目前的
am in my life. There's actually a
人生状态。
sponsor I used to have on the show that
我之前在节目里有一个赞助商，我
I was very big on. And I just stopped um
非常支持他们。但我后来
I stopped consuming the product. They
停止了使用他们的产品。他们
offered me £6 million
给我开出了600万英镑（
which is about what $8 million to
约合800万美元）的价码，让我再合作
continue for another year and a half.
一年半。
And I said like it just wouldn't I'm
我说，我即将
about to basically start
开始
talking about and investing in the
谈论和投资与我之前
antithesis of what you do.
所做的事情截然相反的东西，所以这对我来说太不合适了。
Yeah. So, I had to turn down that $7
是的。所以，我不得不拒绝了那700万美元
million, which is a lot of money for
，这对
anybody.
任何人来说都是一笔巨款。
Yeah.
是的。
But it's because my life shifted and I
但这是因为我的人生发生了转变，我朝着
shifted in a different direction. People
不同的方向发展了。人们
don't see those things. They they don't
看不到这些。 他们
see that the this foreign government
看不到，某个外国政府
comes along and offers you $4 million to
会给你400万美元，让你
go and talk about their country or to go
去他们的国家演讲，或者去
do the dario in their country. They
他们的国家做些事情。他们
don't see those decisions that you make.
看不到你做出的这些决定。
But I think hopefully if you listen to
但我希望，如果你听
me long enough, you'll see a through
我讲得足够久，你就能明白
authentic to me.
我所言不虚。
Yeah. And I think that so you've already
是的。我想你已经
figured it out. And the other thing that
明白了。还有一件事
I would do and say anybody your age and
我想对像你这个年纪的人说，
because I wish I'd done it is start
因为我真希望自己当初也这么做了，那就是
focusing on longevity in your 30s. Start
从30多岁就开始关注长寿。开始
thinking about what you eat and what you
思考你的饮食、
drink and how much sleep you do and how
饮水、睡眠和
much exercise you have. You're you could
运动量。你可以
live to 120 years old. I mean
活到120岁。我的意思是，
crazy,
这太疯狂了，你知道，如果你
understand if you're wearing a whoop,
明白我的意思，如果你戴着Whoop，
you know what I'm talking about. It's
你就知道我在说什么了。
sort of I am very very uh focused on
我非常非常注重
what I do and exercise and what I eat
我的所作所为、运动、饮食等等
and all that. Um, but uh that makes you
。嗯，这会让你
feel healthier and more and just better
感觉更健康，更快乐。
about the your day as you go through it.
你的一天就是这样度过的。
But the fact that you figured that out
但你
at your age because most people your age
在这个年纪就明白这一点，这很了不起，因为大多数和你同龄的人
would have taken the 7 million pounds or
都会接受那700万英镑（或
whatever it was, that would have been a
其他数额），那将是一个
huge mistake because now the next
巨大的错误。因为现在，
product that you do endorse, I will know
你代言的下一个产品，我可以
with certainty that you use it because
肯定地说你用过，因为
you told me this.
你告诉我了这一点。
We have a closing tradition on this
我们这个播客有个结尾的传统，上一位
podcast where the last guest leaves a
嘉宾会给下一位嘉宾留一个
question for the next guest, not knowing
问题，但不知道问题会
who they're leaving it for. And the
留给谁。
question that was left for you, funnily
有趣的是，留给你的问题，
enough, I feel like I might have asked
我觉得我可能也会问
it, is where do you believe happiness
，是：你认为幸福的
really comes from?
真正来源是什么？
You know, I think the answer is very
你知道，我认为答案很
simple. Consistently achieving your
简单。那就是持续地实现你的
goals because happiness is not a
目标，因为幸福不是
destination. It's a journey. That's what
终点，而是一段旅程。就是这样
it is.
。
So you have to set those goals whether
所以你必须设定目标，无论
it's noise to signal going full circle.
是短期目标、
talked about or long-term, whatever it
长期目标还是其他什么目标
is, it's consistently achieving those
，只要持续地实现这些
goals, you will be happy. Consistently
目标，你就会幸福。如果一直
not achieving them, you'll be unhappy
无法实现目标，你就会不幸福，
because it is not
因为幸福不是
a destination. Happiness is not a
终点。幸福
destination ever. It's a mistake that's
永远不是终点。 一个
so elusive. I mean,
难以捉摸的错误。我的意思是，
it's just not a destination. It's a
它不是一个终点，而是一段
journey. That's it. This is one of the
旅程。就是这样。
great things you've taught me today and
今天你教给我并
reaffirmed for me today is this idea of
再次印证的最重要的一点就是
like signal and noise and radical
信号与噪声以及彻底的
prioritization because kind of
优先级排序的概念，因为这与
dovetailing into what we were just
我们刚才
talking about. When you have a lot of
讨论的内容不谋而合。当你有很多
opportunity, it gets even harder, I
机会时，我
think, to know which ones should be
认为，要知道哪些机会值得
taking your 18 hours a day. This is
你每天投入18个小时就变得更加困难。这正是
something I struggle with.
我一直在努力克服的。
You should feel it. You know, you're
你应该有这种感觉。你知道，
you're kind of a weird dude because
你有点特别，因为
you're like a 70-year-old man in a
你就像一个70岁的老人，却拥有
30-year-old body. Like you've got you've
30岁的身体。你拥有
which most people don't have at your
大多数人在你这个年纪所不具备的智慧和经验
age. But deals
。但是，对于交易，
There's a certain feeling that you if if
你应该有一种感觉，那就是这是
you should feel that it's a good deal.
一笔好交易。这种感觉
It should it should be in your gut. And
应该发自你的内心。
I've learned this. There's many deals
我已经明白了这一点。很多交易
that sound great that when I just do the
听起来都很棒，但当我仔细考虑之后……
gut check, I don't participate in. They
直觉，我不参与。他们
just don't give me and that came from
根本不给我这种机会，这是我的
experience. But you seem to have that in
经验之谈。但你似乎以
some weird way to avoid that one we just
某种奇怪的方式避免了我们刚才
talked about. That's it. It's it's it's
讨论的那种情况。就是这样。这是
an intuitive feeling that you generally
一种直觉，通常是
get by having a lot of winners and
通过长期经历许多成功和
losers over time.
失败而获得的。
But you seem to have accelerated that
但你似乎以
somehow. It's an intuitive nature of
某种方式加速了这种感觉。这是一种直觉，让你知道
where you want to get to and what it's
你想达到什么目标，以及
going to take to get there. And there's
需要付出什么才能达到目标。在这个过程中肯定会有
going to be sacrifice along the way.
牺牲。
It's never about the money. Never. It's
这从来都与金钱无关。绝对不是。这与
not about the money. It's, you know,
金钱无关。你知道，关键在于
it's do I want to achieve that goal?
我是否想要实现这个目标。
You know, I'm having a it's it's just a
你知道，我最近遇到了一件很
weird thing because I I had a similar
奇怪的事，因为就在几天前，我遇到了类似的
situation just a couple of days ago,
情况，
you know, when somebody approached me
有人找到我
and said, "Look, can you get behind this
说：“听着，你能支持这个项目吗？
and and back it and I'll pay you a ton,
我会付你一大笔钱，一大笔钱
like just a crazy amount of money." And
。”
I thought, "Do I actually want to spend
我当时想：“我真的想花
one hour pursuing that?"
一个小时吗？” 继续做这件事吗？”
And I went back and said, "Look, um, no.
然后我回去说：“听着，嗯，不。
I I just it's just not interesting. I I
我觉得它一点都不有趣。 我就是……
just I don't I can't see my I can't see
我无法想象
myself getting involved in that
自己卷入那种
narrative, which was it was a
叙事中，那是一个
complicated situation, but
复杂的情况，
and then he said, "Look,
然后他说：“听着，
how about I give you two and a half% of
我给你公司百分之二点五的股份怎么样
the company?"
？”
I said, "No,
我说：“不，
I I just don't want to be associated." I
我就是不想和他们有任何瓜葛。”
you know, it's just it's the same idea.
你知道，其实就是同一个意思。
It would intuitively
直觉告诉我，
It was noise.
那是噪音。   是的
Yeah. And what that would do is some
。 这样做会导致你在
the future that you you you you pursued
未来错失一些你不知道的机会，因为你追求的
some goal that somehow tainted your
某些目标在某种程度上玷污了你的
brand and that opportunity never comes
品牌，而这些机会最终永远不会
to you. You you're you're the you're the
属于你。 你，你是
captain of your brand. You got to you
你品牌的掌舵人。 你必须在整个
the journey. It's hard. It's really
过程中不断定义自己。 这很难。
hard, you know. It's it's uh
你知道，这真的很难。 这……这
it's really hard. and that and that if
真的很难。 而且，如果
you, you will have chosen unwisely
你最终遭遇失败，那一定是你在某些方面做出了不明智的选择
somewhere. But it better not be from
。 但最好别是
money. That's there should never be an
钱。 也就是说，你永远不应该
amount that you would take because if
接受任何金额，因为如果
your gut says no, it doesn't matter what
你的直觉告诉你“不”，那么
the money is. Not after what you've
钱有多少都无关紧要。 在你取得如此成就之后，就不是这样了
achieved. I mean, you don't need to buy
。 我的意思是，你不再需要购买
a guarantee anymore. You got it. I'm
保修了。 答对了。 我
assuming you've put some away. I mean,
猜你已经储存了一些。 我的意思是，
it's very simple.
这很简单。
If you've got five million bucks in the
如果你银行里有五百万美元
bank, you can do whatever you want. Now,
，你想做什么都可以。 现在，
I mean, it's may sound I want more, but
我的意思是，这听起来可能像是我想要更多，但
that is enough under cat. Always have
猫咪主题已经足够了。
always I have an account that just sits
我一直都有一个账户，里面存着
there with 5 million bucks in it in T
500 万美元的
bills. I never touch it.
国债。 我从不碰它。
That's my nest egg.
那是我的积蓄。
Kevin, thank you. You go.
凯文，谢谢你。 你去。
[Music]
[音乐]